<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>Fundamental Analysis</title>
        <description>Economic events influence the market in many ways. Find out how upcoming events are likely to impact your positions.</description>
        <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 23:27:28 +1100</lastBuildDate>
                    <item>
                <title>The USD rose to a 2-month high</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>Last week, the global reserve currency finally gained buyer support and recorded a rise to 2-month highs, as investor demand for risky assets declined.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/usd-rallies-two-month-highs"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_95361347611610966903864.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last week, the global reserve currency finally gained buyer support and recorded a rise to 2-month highs. Investor demand for risky assets declined at the end of the week as stock indices and the bond market adjusted, contributing to positive U.S. dollar sentiment.</span></p>
<h2><b>USD</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Economic data in the U.S. was relatively good, although it did not dissipate concerns that the economic recovery continued to lose momentum. Retail sales were 2.9% higher in December year-on-year, but fell -1.9% compared to November and disappointed market expectations. The country&rsquo;s annual inflation was 1.4% in December and remained stable over the last quarter. Industrial production continued to recover gradually and in December was -3.6% lower than a year ago. The number of new jobless claims rose from 0.79 to 0.97 million a week.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last week, the rate of spread of the coronavirus slowed down. The situation in the U.S. reflected global trends and the weekly average fell from 246 to 228 thousand cases per day. The number of people vaccinated in the country rose from 7.1 to 13.7 million and hinted at an accelerating process. In the United States as a whole, 4.2% of the population have already been vaccinated. Among other important news was the situation in the United Kingdom, where a mutated strain of the virus is spreading. U.K. ranked 5th in the world in terms of the number of cases, with the average slowing slightly from 60,000 to 48,000 cases a day. The situation was also significantly deteriorating in Spain, where the number of infections jumped from 10 to 40 thousand per day in a few weeks and the country was already recording the third wave of the virus. Around 40 million doses of the vaccine were injected worldwide, a significant increase from last week&rsquo;s level of 19 million.</span></p>
<h2><b>Euro</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The main currency pair EUR/USD reflected the strengthening trends of the U.S. dollar and fell to the level of 1,207 and a 50-day moving average on the daily chart. There was little economic data coming from Europe. The European industrial volumes in November were -0.6% lower than a year ago, but recovered and grew by 2.5% compared to October. The German economy contracted by -5.0% in 2020, affected by both declining global demand and domestic economic quarantine constraints due to the epidemic. The EUR/USD pair closed the week depreciating -1.2%.</span></p>
<h2><b>JPY</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The main Asian pair, USD/JPY, fluctuated mostly below the 104.0 level and below a 50-day moving average on the daily chart. No relevant economic data was published. USD/JPY ended the week dropping -0.1%.</span></p>
<h2><b>GBP</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the first half of the week, the British pound once again tried to break through the 1,370 resistance level against the U.S. dollar, but later did not keep up with the sentiment of the strengthening U.S. dollar and the pair depreciated. Among the economic data was a change in the country&rsquo;s economy, which recorded a -2.6% decline from the previous month. This was the first negative month after 6 positive months and probably reflected significant constraints on the spread of the coronavirus. Industrial production volumes were -4.7% lower than a year ago. GBP/USD ended the week up 0.1%.</span></p>
<h2><b>Economic Events</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This week will start with important data from China, where industrial production, retail and economic growth figures will be released. Monday will be a non-working day in the U.S. German inflation rates and ZEW economic index data will be expected on Tuesday. Investors will monitor inflation rates in U.K. and Europe on Wednesday. Japan&rsquo;s export data and a press release from the country&rsquo;s central bank after the members&rsquo; meeting will be expected on Thursday. A meeting of the European Central Bank will follow and decisions on interest rates and additional incentives will be expected. Japan's inflation data and preliminary results of the major economies manufacturing PMI indices will be expected on Friday. The week will end with U.K. retail sales data and U.S. existing home sales results.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Admiral Markets market sentiment data, 80% of investors have long positions in the EUR/USD pair (increased +42 percentage points from last week). In the main Asian pair USD/JPY, 71% of investors have long positions (up 32 percentage points). In the GBP/USD pair, 59% of participants expect a rise (up 9 percentage points). Such market data is interpreted as contraindicative, therefore EUR/USD, GBP/USD and USD/JPY pairs are expected to depreciate. The analysis of positioning data needs to be combined with fundamental projections and technical analysis.</span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sources: bloomberg.com, reuters.com, Admiral Markets MT4 Supreme Edition, investing.com</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Live_Account-14.png" alt="Trade Forex &amp; CFDs" /></a></p>
<p><b><em>INFORMATION ON ANALYTICAL MATERIALS</em></b><b>:</b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The data provided provides additional information on all analyzes, estimates, forecasts, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other evaluations or similar information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the Admiral Markets website. Before making any investment decisions, pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<ol>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This is a marketing communication. The content is posted for informational purposes only and should not be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and is not subject to any prohibition on pre-dissemination of investment research.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Each investment decision is made by each client alone, while Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) will not be liable for any loss or damage arising from such a decision, whether based on content or not.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> In order to protect the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for the prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The analysis is prepared by an independent analyst, Carolina Caro, SEO implementer (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimates.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> While all reasonable efforts are made to ensure that all sources of content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, accurate, and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee accuracy. or integrity of any information contained in the Analysis.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Any past performance or modelling of the financial instruments indicated in the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee, or implication of Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may rise and fall, and the preservation of the asset's value is not guaranteed.</span></em></li>
</ol>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7. Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may generate profit or loss. Before you start trading, make sure you fully understand the </span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">risks</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 23:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/600568012db741610967041.jpeg" length="192254" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/usd-rallies-two-month-highs</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/usd-rallies-two-month-highs</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Weekly Market Outlook: Central banks, earnings and the Presidential Inauguration</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>Discover the most important economic reports to watch in the week ahead and the major corporate trading updates to be aware of.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/weekly-market-outlook-18-jan"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_83123064211610965424715.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&rsquo;s a big week ahead for traders and investors and economic data, company reports and politics all take centre stage. The 59th Presidential Inauguration is set to take place on Wednesday 20 January. However, investors will be on edge following the attack on Capitol Hill in Washington.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From an economic standpoint, traders will be focused on the Bank of Canada statement and press conference on Wednesday, the Bank of Japan statement and press conference on Thursday and the European Central Bank (ECB) press conference at 1.30pm GMT on Thursday as well.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stock markets have already reacted to Joe Biden&rsquo;s $1.9 trillion stimulus package announced and will now be focused on the earnings season which kicked off last week. With mixed results from banks such as JP Morgan and Citigroup, all eyes turn to heavyweights such as Goldman Sachs, Morgan Stanley and Bank of America.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can learn more about some of the global themes affecting the markets in this selection of education articles:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/shares/best-shares-to-buy"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Best Shares to Buy in 2021</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/general-trading/beat-the-market-dogs-of-the-dow"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to Beat the Market? Try Dogs of the Dow 2021</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/shares/stock-sectors"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 11 Sectors of the Stock Market You Need to Know!</span></a></li>
</ul>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Weekly Forex Calendar</span></h2>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_41630842221610965507840.png" /></span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Forex Calendar provided by Admiral Markets UK Ltd.</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that three times a week, three professional traders talk through the markets live and show you how to identify potential trading opportunities? Reserve your complimentary spot in the Admiral Markets Spotlight webinar now by clicking the banner below!</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/webinars"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Advanced_Trading_Webinars_CTA-1.jpg" alt="Free Trading Webinars" /></a></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Trader&rsquo;s Radar - ECB Press Conference</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Thursday 21 January at 1.30 pm GMT, all eyes will be firmly on the euro and the ECB Press Conference. While no changes are expected in the bank&rsquo;s monetary policy, traders will be keen to learn more about the bank&rsquo;s view of the euro. The currency appreciated more than 16% against the US dollar last year, from March lows to January highs.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The currency already started to give back some gains last week, largely thanks to a more bullish US dollar across the board. However, the euro fell against most other major currencies as traders adjust portfolios in front of the high risk press conference.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the &euro;750 billion stimulus recovery fund has already started to be distributed, many analysts believe this is not enough now that many countries have gone back in lockdown. Some analysts believe the Eurozone is now facing a double-dip recession and the growing political crisis in Italy - where the ruling coalition party is on the verge of collapse - is not helping.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_11901614331610965564530.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5, EURUSD, Monthly - Data range: from Sep 1, 2005, to Jan 15, 2021. Performed on Jan 15, 2021, at 7:00 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the long-term monthly chart above of EURUSD, it&rsquo;s clear to see the long-term descending trend line from the highs of 2007, 2011, 2013 and 2017. Price finally broke through this level of resistance in late 2020.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the price has now moved straight into another long-term resistance line, as shown by the black horizontal line at around the 1.2239 price level. This level provided significant support in 2010 and 2013, before breaking through in 2014 and finding resistance in 2017.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Traders may well use these levels to lean against for short positions as the narrative surrounding the euro and US dollar starts to change. A break back above this horizontal resistance line would be a clear sign of strength from the buyers.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you&rsquo;re feeling inspired and ready to trade live in the market, you can open a live trading account by clicking on the banner below and accessing an impressive range of trading features to support you in your journey.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Live_Account-14.png" alt="Trade Forex &amp; CFDs" /></a></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Corporate trading updates and stock indices</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last week, global stock markets struggled to continue the gains initiated from the beginning of the year. European stock indices spent most the recent week in a tight trading range, even after the DAX 30 broke to record highs only recently. While US stock indices tried to push higher before settling down for the week, it was Asia stock market indices which performed the best.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many analysts and fund managers are now looking towards emerging markets, after bemoaning the lofty valuations in the US stock market. Some are also concerned about Joe Biden&rsquo;s plans which could derail any further momentum towards the upside.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the distribution of flows has been unequal in most cases as some stocks continue to outperform. For example, smaller tech companies have received a boost from investors who are exiting the bigger tech names which are more overstretched.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_20939338941610965629179.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5, SP500, Daily - Data range: from Apr 22, 2020, to Jan 15, 2021, performed on Jan 15, 2021, at 8:30 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Past five-year performance of the S&amp;P 500 circa: 2020 = +16.17%, 2019 = +29.09%, 2018 = -5.96%, 2017 = +19.08%, 2016 = +8.80%, 2015 = -0.82%.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The daily chart of the S&amp;P 500 above is still confirming an uptrend with the 20-period (blue) 50-period (red), 100-period (green) and 200-period (black) exponential moving averages all moving upwards. These moving averages have not only helped to confirm the trend bias but have also acted as support levels for buyers.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Both traders and investors will also be watching the companies that are due to report their latest quarterly earrings. Some of these include:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tuesday 19 January - Bank of America, Goldman Sachs, Halliburton, Netflix</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wednesday 20 January - ASML, Morgan Stanley, Alcoa, Procter &amp; Gamble</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thursday 21 January - Intel, IBM</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Friday 22 January - Schlumberger</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that you can use the Trading Central Technical Ideas Lookup indicator to find actionable trading ideas on this index and thousands of other instruments across Forex, stocks, indices, commodities and more?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can get this indicator completely FREE by upgrading your MetaTrader 5 trading platform provided by Admiral Markets UK Ltd to the exclusive Admiral Markets Supreme Edition!</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-se"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/MT5_SE_dark-2.png" alt="Download MetaTrader 5 Supreme Edition " /></a></p>
<p><b><em>INFORMATION ABOUT ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</em></b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The given data provides additional information regarding all analysis, estimates, prognosis, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other similar assessments or information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the website of Admiral Markets. Before making any investment decisions please pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">1.This is a marketing communication. The content is published for informative purposes only and is in no way to be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and that it is not subject to any prohibition on dealing ahead of the dissemination of investment research.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">2.Any investment decision is made by each client alone whereas Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) shall not be responsible for any loss or damage arising from any such decision, whether or not based on the content.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">3.With view to protecting the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">4.The Analysis is prepared by an independent analyst Jitan Solanki, Freelance Contributor (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimations.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">5.Whilst every reasonable effort is taken to ensure that all sources of the content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, precise and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of any information contained within the Analysis.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">6.Any kind of past or modelled performance of financial instruments indicated within the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee or implication by Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may both increase and decrease and the preservation of the asset value is not guaranteed.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7.Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may result in losses or profit. Before you start trading, please ensure that you fully understand the</span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com.au/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> risks involved</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 23:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/600562a1b79861610965665.jpeg" length="215690" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/weekly-market-outlook-18-jan</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/weekly-market-outlook-18-jan</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>U.S. dollar bounced higher from the lows</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>The global reserve currency began depreciating last week to its lowest point since March 2018, but has since been fighting to regain value.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/usd-rallying-against-lows"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_23253736911610354683926.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The global reserve currency began depreciating last week to its lowest point since March 2018, as financial markets were optimistic and investors had high-risk sentiment, prompting market participants to sell the safe currency - U.S. dollar. Nevertheless, on Wednesday and for the rest of the week, the U.S. dollar found support levels and rebounded slightly from its lowest point in nearly 3 years.</span></p>
<h2><b>USD</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Economic data in the U.S. varied. The ISM manufacturing PMI index was at 60.7 points and exceeded expectations and suggested further growth. The services sector index was 57.2 points and also showed rapid growth despite record pandemic numbers. Labour market figures were worse than previously and the country lost 140,000 jobs in December, the first negative month since April 2020. The unemployment rate remained at 6.7%. The number of new jobless claims remained stable at 0.79 million a week.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The spread of the coronavirus intensified in early January after a calmer festive period. The U.S. weekly average rose to 246,000, and the number of one-day cases reached 300,000 on Friday, according to data. In India, the number of new cases has stabilized at the level of 18 thousand per day. Much attention is being paid to the United Kingdom, which is witnessing a new mutation in the virus that is spreading extremely rapidly, and the country currently has about 60,000 cases per day. It is estimated that 19 million doses of the vaccine have already been injected worldwide, and 7.1 million in the U.S., a significant increase from the 3.5 million level last week.</span></p>
<h2><b>Euro</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The main currency pair EUR/USD had risen to 1,235 points in the first half of the week, but later lost the gains and ended the week at 1,222 points. Among the economic data in Europe was the manufacturing PMI index, which stood at 55.2 points and indicated growth. The services sector index was 46.4 points and, although up from last month, still remained in negative territory. European preliminary annual inflation was negative at -0.3% in December. The EUR/USD pair ended the week unchanged.</span></p>
<h2><b>JPY</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The most important Asian pair, USD/JPY, largely reflected U.S. dollar trends and depreciated at the beginning of the week, but then rebounded. Among the economic data was the manufacturing sector PMI index, which was 50.0 points, and the services sector, which was 47.7 points. USD/JPY ended the week up 0.6%.</span></p>
<h2><b>GBP</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The British pound hit 1,370 against the U.S. dollar on Monday, but later depreciated for the rest of the week and lost positions. Among the economic data was the manufacturing PMI index, which stood at 57.5 points and showed growth. The service sector had 49.4 points and showed only a very limited negative impact of quarantine on sentiment. GBP/USD ended the week with depreciation of -0.7%.</span></p>
<h2><b>Economic Events</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This week will start fairly calmly and important economic indicators are not planned on Monday and Tuesday. European industrial production data and U.S. inflation figures for December will be expected on Wednesday. On Thursday, the focus will shift to preliminary data for the fourth quarter of the German economy. The results of industrial production in U.K. will be monitored on Friday, followed by U.S. retail sales and industrial production.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Admiral Markets market sentiment data, 38% of investors have long positions in the EUR/USD pair (down -22 percentage points from last week). In the main Asian pair USD/JPY, 39% of investors have long positions (fell by -9 percentage points). In the GBP/USD pair, 50% of participants expect a rise (up 19 percentage points). Such market data is interpreted as contraindicative, so EUR/USD and USD/JPY are expected to rise and the GBP/USD pair remains in a neutral position. The analysis of positioning data needs to be combined with fundamental projections and technical analysis.</span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sources: bloomberg.com, reuters.com, Admiral Markets MT4 Supreme Edition, investing.com</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Live_Account-14.png" alt="Trade Forex &amp; CFDs" /></a></p>
<p><b>INFORMATION ON ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The data provided provides additional information on all analyzes, estimates, forecasts, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other evaluations or similar information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the Admiral Markets website. Before making any investment decisions, pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<ol>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This is a marketing communication. The content is posted for informational purposes only and should not be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and is not subject to any prohibition on pre-dissemination of investment research.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Each investment decision is made by each client alone, while Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) will not be liable for any loss or damage arising from such a decision, whether based on content or not.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> In order to protect the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for the prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The analysis is prepared by an independent analyst, Carolina Caro, SEO implementer (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimates.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> While all reasonable efforts are made to ensure that all sources of content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, accurate, and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee accuracy. or integrity of any information contained in the Analysis.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Any past performance or modelling of the financial instruments indicated in the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee, or implication of Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may rise and fall, and the preservation of the asset's value is not guaranteed.</span></em></li>
</ol>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7. Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may generate profit or loss. Before you start trading, make sure you fully understand the </span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">risks</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 21:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/5ffc107da874f1610354813.jpeg" length="201254" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/usd-rallying-against-lows</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/usd-rallying-against-lows</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Weekly Market Outlook: The US dollar, stimulus and stocks in focus</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>Discover the most important economic reports to watch in the week ahead and the major corporate trading updates to be aware of.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/weekly-market-outlook-11-jan"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_75015714911610352521922.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&rsquo;s setting up to be another interesting week for financial markets as the US dollar brushed off the worst jobs report since April 2020 last week. Market participants were shocked when 150,000 jobs were lost in the economy during December against an expected 50,000 increase in jobs.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Surprisingly, the US dollar rallied higher in the short-term after the news as traders question just how much lower the worst-performing currency of the past several months can go. Now that the Democratic Party has gained full control of the Congress, larger stimulus measures are expected but may already be priced into markets.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The stimulus expectations have helped US stock market indices to new all-time highs with European stock indices also enjoying some of the positive flows. With a relatively quiet economic calendar, all eyes will be on these larger themes.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can learn more about some of these themes in this selection of education articles:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/shares/best-shares-to-buy"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Best Shares to Buy in 2021</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/general-trading/trading-us-dollar-index"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to Trade the US Dollar Index</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/general-trading/beat-the-market-dogs-of-the-dow"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to Beat the Market? Try Dogs of the Dow 2021</span></a></li>
</ul>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Weekly Forex Calendar</span></h2>
<p><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_94096131251610352710811.png" /></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Forex Calendar provided by Admiral Markets UK Ltd.</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that three times a week, three professional traders talk through the markets live and show you how to identify potential trading opportunities? Reserve your complimentary spot in the Admiral Markets Spotlight webinar now by clicking the banner below!</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/webinars"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Advanced_Trading_Webinars_CTA-1.jpg" alt="Free Trading Webinars" /></a></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Trader&rsquo;s Radar - The US Dollar</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For much of 2020, the biggest theme in the currency market was the weakening US dollar. The anticipation of a large stimulus package, a divided country and poor handling of the coronavirus pandemic helped the US dollar to remain one of the weakest currencies against most of the G10.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last week, the US Non-Farm Payroll figure confirmed the weakness plaguing the economy. Analysts were expecting 50,000 jobs to be added to the economy but instead, it lost 150,000. However, the unemployment rate ticked higher as did hourly earnings. The US dollar subsequently rallied higher on the news announcement but it may be too early to get excited.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The US dollar index - an index of the US dollar against a basket of other currencies - is fast approaching some critical levels of historical support. From this technical basis, a reversal of fortunes could be on the cards. However, the zone of support is large, as shown in the long-term chart below:</span></p>
<p><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_1496132461610352718082.png" /></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5, USDX, Monthly - Data range: from Nov 1, 2004, to Jan 8, 2021. Performed on Jan 8, 2021, at 7:00 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The zonal area of support sits between the two lower black horizontal support lines on the chart in between the 88.00 and 89.00 levels. However, the price has moved meaningfully into this level suggesting there could still be some downside yet to come but unlikely to repeat the momentum we have had over the past few months.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other US dollar related currency pairs are also approaching levels of support, such as USDCAD as shown by the ascending support level in the long-term monthly chart below:</span></p>
<p><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_37198532871610352725527.png" /></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5, USDCAD, Monthly - Data range: from Dec 1, 2005, to Jan 8, 2021. Performed on Jan 8, 2021, at 7:30 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The real test for the US dollar may be dependent on how investors weigh up the risks of the world&rsquo;s second-largest currency the euro. Watching price action up until the European Central Bank press conference on the 21 January could be interesting in identifying where larger institutions see the next big move.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you&rsquo;re feeling inspired and ready to trade live in the market, you can open a live trading account by clicking on the banner below and accessing an impressive range of trading features to support you in your journey.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Live_Account-14.png" alt="Trade Forex &amp; CFDs" /></a></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Corporate trading updates and stock indices</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Global stock market indices have continued their rallies higher to start the year. Expectations of big stimulus measures coming from Joe Biden and the Democrats have helped underpin demand for US stocks.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, it is worthwhile keeping an eye on some of the sector plays that are developing, as the rally higher has been uneven. While long-term investors have continued to rotate into value stocks, we are now starting to see a rotation back into growth stocks.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">European stock markets have also enjoyed some of the positive flows from the US. Currently, the DAX 30 is trading at record highs with France 40 and FTSE 100 still some way off their respective all-high price levels. On a successful rollout of the coronavirus vaccine, European stocks may be more favoured due to the undervaluation compared to other stock markets.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_88817367981610352800875.png" /></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5, SP500, Daily - Data range: from Apr 17, 2020, to Jan 8, 2021, performed on Jan 8, 2021, at 8:30 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Past five-year performance of the S&amp;P 500 circa: 2020 = +16.17%, 2019 = +29.09%, 2018 = -5.96%, 2017 = +19.08%, 2016 = +8.80%, 2015 = -0.82%.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The daily chart of the S&amp;P 500 still confirms an uptrend with the 50-period (red), 100-period (green) and 200-period (blue) exponential moving averages all moving upwards. You can also learn more about specific stock plays that could be interesting in 2021 in:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/shares/best-shares-to-buy"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Best Shares to Buy for 2021</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/general-trading/beat-the-market-dogs-of-the-dow"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to Beat the Market? Try Dogs of the Dow 2021</span></a></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&rsquo;s also the start of US earnings season with JP Morgan, Citigroup and Wells Fargo reporting on Friday.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that you can use the Trading Central Technical Ideas Lookup indicator to find actionable trading ideas on this index and thousands of other instruments across Forex, stocks, indices, commodities and more?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can get this indicator completely FREE by upgrading your MetaTrader 5 trading platform provided by Admiral Markets UK Ltd to the exclusive Admiral Markets Supreme Edition!</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-se"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/MT5_SE_dark-2.png" alt="Download MetaTrader 5 Supreme Edition " /></a></p>
<p><b><em>INFORMATION ABOUT ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</em></b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The given data provides additional information regarding all analysis, estimates, prognosis, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other similar assessments or information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the website of Admiral Markets. Before making any investment decisions please pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">1.This is a marketing communication. The content is published for informative purposes only and is in no way to be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and that it is not subject to any prohibition on dealing ahead of the dissemination of investment research.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">2.Any investment decision is made by each client alone whereas Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) shall not be responsible for any loss or damage arising from any such decision, whether or not based on the content.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">3.With view to protecting the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">4.The Analysis is prepared by an independent analyst Jitan Solanki, Freelance Contributor (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimations.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">5.Whilst every reasonable effort is taken to ensure that all sources of the content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, precise and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of any information contained within the Analysis.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">6.Any kind of past or modelled performance of financial instruments indicated within the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee or implication by Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may both increase and decrease and the preservation of the asset value is not guaranteed.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7.Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may result in losses or profit. Before you start trading, please ensure that you fully understand the</span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com.au/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> risks involved</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 21:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/5ffc08df938c61610352863.jpeg" length="273000" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/weekly-market-outlook-11-jan</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/weekly-market-outlook-11-jan</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>The USD continues to see trouble regaining value</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>Last week, sellers continued to put pressure on the U.S. dollar and the global reserve currency fell to new lows in 2020.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/usd-depreciation-continues"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_99747850411609747517309.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last week, sellers put pressure on the U.S. dollar and the global reserve currency fell to new lows in 2020.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Due to the holiday period and short work week, economic data in the U.S. was very limited. The most important were pending home sales, the volumes of which increased by about 16% compared to the same period a year ago. The country&rsquo;s real estate market remains very active, with property prices rising by about 7% per year, loan interest rates falling by about -1%, and the number of homes sold in the market one of the lowest in a decade, reducing supply. The number of new jobless claims remained stable at 0.79 million a week.</span></p>
<h2><b>USD</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The spread of the coronavirus infection remains high. The situation in the United States remains relatively negative, with about 190,000 new cases of the virus recorded each day. The country has already vaccinated 3.5 million times and, although significantly behind schedule, is expected to catch up in the first quarter of 2021. The vaccination process is most advanced in Israel, where 10% of the population has already been vaccinated. In India, a further slowdown was recorded and the average number of cases dropped to 17,000. In Brazil, the trend remains stable at 35,000 cases per day. In Russia, it changed insignificantly and there were 28,000 thousand cases. In France and Italy, the situation was stable, but in U.K. further sharp growth was recorded at 57,000 per day.</span></p>
<h2><b>Euro</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The major currency pair EUR/USD rose briefly to new highs in 2020 in the second half of the week, at 1,230, but did not last long and depreciated on Thursday afternoon. Due to the important economic data of the festive period, the European data was not published. The EUR/USD pair ended the week up 0.3%.</span></p>
<h2><b>JPY</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The top Asian pair, USD/JPY, returned to 9-month lows and closed at 103.3 points. Among the economic news was the change in industrial volumes in November, which showed a contraction of -3.4% compared to the previous year. USD/JPY ended the week dropping -0.3%.</span></p>
<h2><b>GBP</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The British pound appreciated against the U.S. dollar and ended the week at 1,366-point level, the highest since April 2018. The holiday week was short and there was no economic data. On Thursday night, after the end of 2020, United Kingdom finally withdrew from the European Union, ending almost 5 years of divorce process. Zero import tariffs and zero quotas in trade are mostly applauded, but there are significant increases in administrative requirements, which will force businesses to incur higher staff, documentation and time costs at customs posts. Importantly, the current agreement does not cover the U.K. services sector, particularly finance, which alone paid around 75 billion GBP in taxes in 2018. GBP/USD ended the week up 0.8%.</span></p>
<h2><b>Economic Events</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This week will start with the actual results of the manufacturing PMI index. German retail and labor market data will be expected on Tuesday. Service sector PMI indices will be monitored on Wednesday, and the minutes of the last meeting of the U.S. Federal Reserve will be published in the evening. On Thursday, investors will expect preliminary inflation figures for Europe in December and retail sales in November. On Friday, the focus will be on U.S. labor market data: the number of new jobs created, the unemployment rate and the change in wages.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Admiral Markets market sentiment data, 60% of investors have long positions in the EUR/USD pair (increased +5 percentage points from last week&rsquo;s data). In the main Asian pair USD/JPY, 48% of investors have long positions (up 7 percentage points). In the GBP/USD pair, 31% of participants expect a rise (down 5 percentage points). Such market data is interpreted as contraindicative, so GBP/USD is expected to rise, EUR/USD to fall, and the USD/JPY pair is expected to remain in a neutral position. The analysis of positioning data needs to be combined with fundamental projections and technical analysis.</span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sources: bloomberg.com, reuters.com, Admiral Markets MT4 Supreme Edition, investing.com</span></em></p>
<p><br /><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that with Admiral Markets you can speculate on the price movement of the USD and other major currencies whether they go up or down? This is possible thanks to Contracts for Difference (</span><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/cfd/cfd-trader"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CFDs</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">). Click on the following banner if you want to open a real trading account and start trading:</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Live_Account-14.png" alt="Trade Forex &amp; CFDs" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>INFORMATION ON ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The data provided provides additional information on all analyzes, estimates, forecasts, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other evaluations or similar information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the Admiral Markets website. Before making any investment decisions, pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<ol>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This is a marketing communication. The content is posted for informational purposes only and should not be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and is not subject to any prohibition on pre-dissemination of investment research.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Each investment decision is made by each client alone, while Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) will not be liable for any loss or damage arising from such a decision, whether based on content or not.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> In order to protect the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for the prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The analysis is prepared by an independent analyst, Carolina Caro, SEO implementer (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimates.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> While all reasonable efforts are made to ensure that all sources of content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, accurate, and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee accuracy. or integrity of any information contained in the Analysis.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Any past performance or modelling of the financial instruments indicated in the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee, or implication of Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may rise and fall, and the preservation of the asset's value is not guaranteed.</span></em></li>
</ol>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7. Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may generate profit or loss. Before you start trading, make sure you fully understand the </span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">risks</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 21:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/5ff2cc7a7046a1609747578.jpeg" length="317658" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/usd-depreciation-continues</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/usd-depreciation-continues</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Weekly Market Outlook: US employment and a new UK/EU relationship</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>Discover the most important economic reports to watch in the week ahead and the major corporate trading updates to be aware of.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/weekly-market-outlook-4-jan"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_87256404311609745621094.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first full week of the new year sees traders focus on key economic announcements which includes the US FOMC Meeting Minutes release on Wednesday and US Non-Farm Payroll figures and employment report on Friday. Considering the US dollar was the weakest currency for the last half of 2020 the announcements will be widely watched and could cause significant moves in the US dollar.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Traders will also be digesting the post-Brexit trade deal struck between EU and UK negotiators just before Christmas. Britain ended its 47-year membership with the now 27-member bloc with analysts mixed on the impact to the UK. The British pound was a strong performer to end 2020 but concerns remain regarding the new coronavirus strain that has caused an increase in lockdown restrictions, making it a currency to watch early on in the year.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Global stock markets had a wild ride in 2020, largely due to the impact of the coronavirus pandemic. However, US indices recorded all-time highs last year and closed much higher than where they started so all eyes will be on whether or not it can continue this year as well. You can learn more about some of these themes in this selection of new education articles:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/general-trading/uk-stock-market-brexit"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investing in the UK Stock Market After Brexit</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/shares/best-coronavirus-vaccine-stocks"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Top Coronavirus Vaccine Stocks to Watch</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/shares/how-to-trade-us-stock-market"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to Trade the US Stock Market</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/shares/best-shares-to-buy"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Best Shares to Buy in 2021</span></a></li>
</ul>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Weekly Forex Calendar</span></h2>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_43266366521609745669970.png" /></span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Forex Calendar provided by Admiral Markets UK Ltd.</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that three times a week, three professional traders talk through the markets live and show you how to identify potential trading opportunities? Reserve your complimentary spot in the Admiral Markets Spotlight webinar now by clicking the banner below!</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/webinars"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Advanced_Trading_Webinars_CTA-1.jpg" alt="Free Trading Webinars" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Trader&rsquo;s Radar - US Non-Farm Payrolls</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This week, all eyes will be on Friday&rsquo;s economic data releases from the Bureau of Labor Statistics at 1.30pm GMT which includes:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Average Hourly Earnings m/m</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Non-Farm Employment Change</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unemployment Rate</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The market isn&rsquo;t expecting much growth but any bigger signs of weakness may affect the US dollar further. The government&rsquo;s huge stimulus plan and a weakening economy helped the US dollar to be one of the weakest currencies of 2020, as shown by the one-year relative performance figures for the US dollar below:</span></p>
<p><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_60769233431609745787081.png" /></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: </span><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.finviz.com/forex_performance.ashx?v=6"><span style="font-weight: 400;">FinViz</span></a></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, in the long-term there could be further pain ahead for the US dollar if the US economy continues to struggle. Technically, the US dollar index - an index of the US dollar against a basket of other currencies - still has more room to roam towards the downside to complete the consolidation pattern shown by the two black horizontal support and resistance lines below:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_12493892841609745817501.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5, USDX, Monthly - Data range: from Oct 1, 2005 to Jan 3, 2021. Performed on Jan 3, 2021, at 7:00 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Historically, the 90.00 level has acted as a price level where significant turns have taken place. Apart from price breaking through the 90.00 price level in 2005 and 2014, the US dollar index has bounced off and changed trend in 2008, 2009 and 2017.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Buyers will be looking at this level closely, which could change the fortunes of the US dollar this year. However, the market will need a trigger which could come from economic data announcements, new policies from when Joe Biden gets sworn in as president or a deterioration in sentiment on other currencies like the euro.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you&rsquo;re feeling inspired and ready to trade live in the market, you can open a live trading account by clicking on the banner below and accessing an impressive range of trading features to support you in your journey.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Live_Account-14.png" alt="Trade Forex &amp; CFDs" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Corporate trading updates and stock indices</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With no major updates on the corporate calendar, all eyes will be on early year flows into global indices and their sectors. Most global stocks markets managed to rally higher last year when a coronavirus vaccine was announced. Many are forecasting that the trend could continue if the vaccine rollout is successful.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the extent of the rally has differed among countries. US stock market indices performed the best in 2020, followed by Asia indices like Japan&rsquo;s Nikke 225 index and then by European indices. This has created an interesting scenario for many investors as US markets look quite toppy while European indices are still undervalued.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Therefore, keep a close eye on rotations across international markets. Individual sectors may also experience some large rotations as investors allocate more capital to infrastructure, renewables and &lsquo;green-recovery&rsquo; stocks to try and capitalise on any of Joe Biden&rsquo;s new policies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The long-term monthly price chart of the S&amp;P 500 stock market index shows a clear uptrend that is still intact:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_57154377651609745947181.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5, SP500, Monthly - Data range: from May 1, 2005, to Jan 3, 2021, performed on Jan 3, 2021, at 8:30 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The long-term monthly price chart of the DAX 30 stock market index shows a lot of choppy price action in between 2005 and 2020.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Price only just managed to pierce through its record high at the end of last year. Could it run and continue this year?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_31591052961609745969720.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5, DAX30, Monthly - Data range: from Jun 1, 2005, to Jan 3, 2021, performed on Jan 3, 2021, at 8:30 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can also learn more about specific stock plays that could be interesting in 2021 in the &lsquo;</span><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/shares/best-shares-to-buy"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Best Shares to Buy for 2021</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rsquo; article.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that you can use the Trading Central Technical Ideas Lookup indicator to find actionable trading ideas on this index and thousands of other instruments across Forex, stocks, indices, commodities and more?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can get this indicator completely FREE by upgrading your MetaTrader 5 trading platform provided by Admiral Markets UK Ltd to the exclusive Admiral Markets Supreme Edition!</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-se"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/MT5_SE_dark-2.png" alt="Download MetaTrader 5 Supreme Edition " /></a></p>
<p><b><em>INFORMATION ABOUT ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</em></b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The given data provides additional information regarding all analysis, estimates, prognosis, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other similar assessments or information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the website of Admiral Markets. Before making any investment decisions please pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">1.This is a marketing communication. The content is published for informative purposes only and is in no way to be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and that it is not subject to any prohibition on dealing ahead of the dissemination of investment research.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">2.Any investment decision is made by each client alone whereas Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) shall not be responsible for any loss or damage arising from any such decision, whether or not based on the content.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">3.With view to protecting the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">4.The Analysis is prepared by an independent analyst Jitan Solanki, Freelance Contributor (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimations.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">5.Whilst every reasonable effort is taken to ensure that all sources of the content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, precise and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of any information contained within the Analysis.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">6.Any kind of past or modelled performance of financial instruments indicated within the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee or implication by Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may both increase and decrease and the preservation of the asset value is not guaranteed.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7.Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may result in losses or profit. Before you start trading, please ensure that you fully understand the</span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com.au/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> risks involved</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 20:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/5ff2c6ac19e6e1609746092.jpeg" length="253434" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/weekly-market-outlook-4-jan</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/weekly-market-outlook-4-jan</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>U.S. dollar fluctuated around a 2-year low</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>The U.S. dollar fluctuated within a narrow range last week when the market was low on liquidity due to the holiday season.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/usd-hovers-two-year-low"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_80610451611609148517410.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The U.S. dollar fluctuated within a narrow range last week when the market was low on liquidity due to the holiday season. The global reserve currency consolidated around the lowest point since April 2018.</span></p>
<h2><b>USD</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the political front, members of the U.S. Congress managed to agree on a 908 billion USD economic stimulus program. It should include funding for small businesses, health check-ups, rent deferral taxes, as well as one-time per capita benefits of 600 USD and an increased unemployment benefit of up to 300 USD per week. The president is scheduled to sign the program earlier this week.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">U.S. economic data was scarce. The country&rsquo;s consumer confidence index was 88.6 and fell short of market expectations of 97.0 points. This is the lowest value of the index since August. Existing homes market activity remained high and annual home sales were 6.69 million a year in November, very close to business cycle highs. Sales of new homes, meanwhile, slowed to 841,000 a year, the third consecutive month in which total sales shifted from 1.0 million a year. The number of new jobless claims fell from 0.89 to 0.80 million a week.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coronavirus activity has slowed somewhat in recent days, but this is likely to be related to less testing for the holiday period. The U.S. situation showed an improvement, with the average number of cases last week falling below 200,000 a day. In India, the positive trend continued, with the number of cases falling below the level of 25,000 per day. In Brazil, too, the number of cases has been lower in recent days than in the last month, which dropped to 35,000 a day. In Russia, the number of new cases remains stable at 29,000. In France, the situation is also stable and the rate of new cases remains relatively low at 15,000. Great Britain rose to sixth place, where the number of new cases jumped to as high as 36,000 a day, largely due to a new mutation in the virus that is more easily and quickly transmitted between people.</span></p>
<h2><b>Euro</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The main currency pair EUR/USD retreated from its highs to 1,218. In Europe, important economic data were not published due to the festive period. The EUR/USD pair ended the week down -0.6%.</span></p>
<h2><b>JPY</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The main Asian pair, USD/JPY, resisted the lows and rose to 103.6. Among the economic data were retail sales in November, which grew 0.7% year-on-year. The country's unemployment rate also fell from 3.1% to 2.9%. USD/JPY ended the week appreciating +0.4%.</span></p>
<h2><b>GBP</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The British pound started the week depreciating against the US dollar to 1.33 level, but news later emerged that England and the European Union had managed to find an agreement on international trade, prompting the pound to recover and the pair jumped to 1.356. This agreement must be approved by both the English Parliament and the European Union institutions before the end of the year for it to enter into force. This is expected to be done in a timely manner, allowing countries to trade duty-free and quota-free in the coming years and not hampering the movement of goods, but regulation and administration will increase, requiring more documentation, time and staff. No economic indicators were published. GBP/USD ended the week up 0.3%.</span></p>
<h2><b>Economic Events</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This week will start on Monday with data from Japanese industrial production. No indicators are planned for Tuesday and Wednesday, and data from the Chinese manufacturing PMI index will be expected on Thursday morning. Also, Thursday is New Year&rsquo;s Eve, so some markets will not be open or close earlier, and Friday will be a non-working day.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Admiral Markets market sentiment data, 55% of investors have long positions in the EUR/USD pair (up 21 percentage points from last week&rsquo;s data). In the major Asian pair USD/JPY, 41% of investors have long positions (down 17 percentage points). In the GBP/USD pair, 36% of participants expect a rise (down 4 percentage points). Such market data is interpreted as contraindicative, so GBP/USD and USD/JPY pairs are expected to rise and EUR/USD to fall. The analysis of positioning data needs to be combined with fundamental projections and technical analysis.</span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sources: bloomberg.com, reuters.com, Admiral Markets MT4 Supreme Edition, investing.com</span></em></p>
<p><br /><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that with Admiral Markets you can speculate on the price movement of the USD and other major currencies whether they go up or down? This is possible thanks to Contracts for Difference (</span><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/cfd/cfd-trader"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CFDs</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">). Click on the following banner if you want to open a real trading account and start trading:</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Live_Account-14.png" alt="Trade Forex &amp; CFDs" /></a></p>
<p><b>INFORMATION ON ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The data provided provides additional information on all analyzes, estimates, forecasts, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other evaluations or similar information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the Admiral Markets website. Before making any investment decisions, pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<ol>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This is a marketing communication. The content is posted for informational purposes only and should not be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and is not subject to any prohibition on pre-dissemination of investment research.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Each investment decision is made by each client alone, while Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) will not be liable for any loss or damage arising from such a decision, whether based on content or not.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> In order to protect the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for the prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The analysis is prepared by an independent analyst, Carolina Caro, SEO implementer (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimates.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> While all reasonable efforts are made to ensure that all sources of content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, accurate, and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee accuracy. or integrity of any information contained in the Analysis.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Any past performance or modelling of the financial instruments indicated in the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee, or implication of Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may rise and fall, and the preservation of the asset's value is not guaranteed.</span></em></li>
</ol>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7. Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may generate profit or loss. Before you start trading, make sure you fully understand the </span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">risks</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 22:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/5fe9a8ec15d8d1609148652.jpeg" length="260313" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/usd-hovers-two-year-low</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/usd-hovers-two-year-low</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>The U.S. dollar continued to depreciate</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>The U.S. dollar depreciated against major currencies last week, bringing the reserve currency index to its lowest point since April 2018.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/usd-continues-depreciation"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_64075258611608550848509.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The U.S. dollar depreciated against major currencies last week, bringing the reserve currency index to its lowest point since April 2018.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">U.S. economic data was positive, but there were visible signs that the recovery was slowing. Retail sales were 4.1% higher than a year ago, but November volumes were -1.1% lower than in October, which worries investors that the recovery is slowing. Industrial production in November was -5.5% lower than a year ago. The preliminary manufacturing PMI index was at 56.5 points and hinted at a further recovery. The number of jobless claims rose from 0.85 to 0.89 million a week.</span></p>
<h2><b>USD</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The coronavirus continues to spread actively around the world and the number of cases remains high. The situation in the U.S. worsened when the country set a dismal double record, with more than 250,000 new cases a day and just over 37,000 deaths. More than 110,000 people have been treated for the virus in the country&rsquo;s hospitals, mostly since the start of the pandemic. In India, a further slowdown in the incidence of diseases from 30,000 to 25,000&nbsp; was seen. In Brazil, the number of cases was stable at the level of 50,000. In Russia, the number of new cases is also stable at 28,000. France remains in fifth place in the world in terms of the total number of cases, but the number of new cases remains relatively low at 15,000. Turkey rose to sixth place, with 30,000 cases recorded daily.</span></p>
<h2><b>Euro</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The major currency pair EUR/USD continued to rise and reached the level of 1,225 points, the highest level since April 2018. Among the economic data was the change in European industrial volumes in October, which were -3.8% lower than a year ago, and the preliminary PMI indices: manufacturing index reached 55.5 and services 47.3. The services sector remains negatively affected by quarantine constraints, but shows a recovery compared to October data. The EUR/USD pair ended the week appreciating +1.2%.</span></p>
<h2><b>JPY</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The main Asian pair USD/JPY continued to depreciate, reaching 103.0 points on Thursday, the lowest point since the March stock market panic, and if not, since November 2016. Among the economic data were industrial production volumes in October, which were -3.0% lower than a year ago, and export volumes in November were -4.2% lower than a year ago. The inflation rate in the country reached -0.9% in November and increased deflationary pressure on the central bank. USD/JPY ended the week depreciating -0.7%.</span></p>
<h2><b>GBP</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The British pound rose against the U.S. dollar to the level of 1.36, which it hit briefly on Thursday. Negotiations on the terms of the Brexit trade remain in the spotlight, with the parties still not reaching an agreement, so there is still a high probability that customs will have to trade with each other, thus complicating the economic situation. The number of unemployed increased by 64 thousand in the country's labour market. Annual inflation fell to 0.3% in November, with preliminary PMI indices standing at 57.3 points in industry and 49.9 points in services. Retail sales grew 2.4% year-on-year. GBP/USD has ended the week appreciating 2.3%.</span></p>
<h2><b>Economic Events</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This week will be quite calm and short due to the Christmas period. No important data is planned on Monday, and the activity of U.S. existing home sales will be monitored on Tuesday. U.S. new home sales figures and the University of Michigan Consumer Confidence Index are expected on Wednesday. Major markets will close earlier on Thursday and there will be a non-working day on Friday.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Admiral Markets market sentiment data, 34% of investors have long positions in the EUR/USD pair (down 12 percentage points from last week). In the main Asian pair USD/JPY, 58% of investors have long positions (down 15 percentage points). In the GBP/USD pair, 40% of participants expect a rise (down 9 percentage points). Such market data is interpreted as contraindicative, so EUR/USD and GBP/USD are expected to rise and USD/JPY to fall. The analysis of positioning data needs to be combined with fundamental projections and technical analysis.</span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sources: bloomberg.com, reuters.com, Admiral Markets MT4 Supreme Edition, investing.com</span></em></p>
<p><br /><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that with Admiral Markets you can speculate on the price movement of the USD and other major currencies whether they go up or down? This is possible thanks to Contracts for Difference (</span><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/cfd/cfd-trader"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CFDs</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">). Click on the following banner if you want to open a real trading account and start trading:</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Live_Account-14.png" alt="Trade Forex &amp; CFDs" /></a></p>
<p><b>INFORMATION ON ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The data provided provides additional information on all analyzes, estimates, forecasts, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other evaluations or similar information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the Admiral Markets website. Before making any investment decisions, pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<ol>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This is a marketing communication. The content is posted for informational purposes only and should not be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and is not subject to any prohibition on pre-dissemination of investment research.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Each investment decision is made by each client alone, while Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) will not be liable for any loss or damage arising from such a decision, whether based on content or not.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> In order to protect the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for the prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The analysis is prepared by an independent analyst, Carolina Caro, SEO implementer (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimates.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> While all reasonable efforts are made to ensure that all sources of content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, accurate, and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee accuracy. or integrity of any information contained in the Analysis.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Any past performance or modelling of the financial instruments indicated in the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee, or implication of Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may rise and fall, and the preservation of the asset's value is not guaranteed.</span></em></li>
</ol>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7. Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may generate profit or loss. Before you start trading, make sure you fully understand the </span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">risks</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/5fe08a487dba21608550984.jpeg" length="317308" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/usd-continues-depreciation</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/usd-continues-depreciation</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Weekly Market Outlook: Brexit, lockdowns and stimulus in focus</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>Discover the most important economic reports to watch in the week ahead and the major corporate trading updates to be aware of.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/weekly-market-outlook-21-dec"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_95897362311608548106800.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The economic calendar is very quiet this week due to the holiday season. However, there are some big themes that will be on the mind of traders and investors considering how to close out their year-end books and start the new year.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">News from the UK government over the weekend of a new coronavirus mutation that is &lsquo;out of control&rsquo; is likely to impact UK markets - and possibly European markets - heavily. Boris Johnson announced sweeping new lockdown restrictions and effectively cancelled Christmas for London and the South East. The fact that there is still no clarity regarding the outcome of UK and EU trade negotiations is likely to weigh on the British pound with Brexit less than two weeks away.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">US stock market indices recorded new all-time highs last week as traders focus on the potential of a breakthrough in stimulus talks. The positive tones have been felt in European markets but to a mixed degree with only the DAX 30 index pushing higher last week. You can learn more about these themes in this selection of recent education articles:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/general-trading/uk-stock-market-brexit"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investing in the UK Stock Market After Brexit</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/forex-strategy/gbp-jpy-investing"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to Trade GBP/JPY</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/shares/best-coronavirus-vaccine-stocks"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Top Coronavirus Vaccine Stocks to Watch</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/shares/how-to-trade-us-stock-market"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to Trade the US Stock Market</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/shares/best-shares-to-buy"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Best Shares to Buy in 2021</span></a></li>
</ul>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Weekly Forex Calendar</span></h2>
<p><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_68425387321608548174948.png" /></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Forex Calendar provided by Admiral Markets UK Ltd.</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that three times a week, three professional traders talk through the markets live and show you how to identify potential trading opportunities? Reserve your complimentary spot in the Admiral Markets Spotlight webinar now by clicking the banner below!&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/webinars"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Advanced_Trading_Webinars_CTA-1.jpg" alt="Free Trading Webinars" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Trader&rsquo;s Radar - Brexit</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With less than a week to go before the UK leaves the EU, all eyes will be on a potential breakthrough in trade negotiations. As it stands, the UK is set to leave the EU at the end of the year and revert to WTO trading tariffs. Sources have said that there is likely to be a decision on whether a deal can be reached or not before Christmas so it&rsquo;s one to watch.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While progress has been made on some of the big areas there remains disagreements on how long it will take to introduce new arrangements around fisheries. The UK has insisted its sovereign rights over its water should be respected from day one and that UK fleets have to keep a larger share of their catches.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The EU has insisted that the transition period needs to be longer with guarantees on access to UK waters and how catches are distributed. While UK MPs have finished for the Christmas break, they may well be called back to ratify any possible deal.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_98565641931608548329847.png" /></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5, GBPUSD, Monthly - Data range: from Nov 1, 2005 to Dec 20, 2020. Performed on Dec 20, 2020, at 7:00 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The British pound vs US dollar exchange rate is currently sitting at a major level of historical horizontal resistance at around 1.3500, as shown by the black horizontal line in the monthly chart above. This could be a make or break area for GBPUSD.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If a deal is announced buyers are likely to be able to break through the 1.3500 level and head towards next resistance at around 1.4300. However, if it is a no-deal scenario the currency pair could reject the 1.3500 level and head back down to major support at the 1.2000 level.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you&rsquo;re feeling inspired and ready to trade live in the market, you can open a live trading account by clicking on the banner below and accessing an impressive range of trading features to support you in your journey.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Live_Account-14.png" alt="Trade Forex &amp; CFDs" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Corporate trading updates and stock indices</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With no major updates on the corporate calendar, all eyes will be on the potential for a stimulus deal to be announced from Congress. Weekend news announcements have been positive regarding the potential for a deal and traders left last week feeling optimistic. This is evident from the fact US indices like the S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq 100 stock market indices recorded new all-time high price levels.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, traders will be interested in global stock markets as we enter the traditional Santa Claus rally period. You can learn more about it and the exact dates for the seasonal rally in the &lsquo;</span><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/shares/santa-claus-rally"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is the Santa Claus rally and how do you trade it?</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rsquo; article.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_76283088541608548432501.png" /></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5, SP500, Daily - Data range: from March 31, 2020, to Dec 20, 2020, performed on Dec 20, 2020, at 8:30 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Past five-year performance of the S&amp;P 500 circa: 2019 = +29.09%, 2018 = -5.96%, 2017 = +19.08%, 2016 = +8.80%, 2015 = -0.82%, 2014 = +12.32%</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the daily chart above of the S&amp;P 500 stock market index, it shows that last week it recorded a new all-time high price level. The uptrend is still confirmed with the 50-period, 100-period and 200-period exponential moving averages all moving higher and separating away from each other.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This could be particularly interesting as we head into the traditional end of year rally which you learn more about in the &lsquo;</span><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/shares/santa-claus-rally"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is the Santa Claus Rally and How Do You Trade It?</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rsquo; article. You can also learn more about specific stock plays that could be interesting in 2021 in the &lsquo;</span><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/shares/best-shares-to-buy"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Best Shares to Buy for 2021</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rsquo; article.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that you can use the Trading Central Technical Ideas Lookup indicator to find actionable trading ideas on this index and thousands of other instruments across Forex, stocks, indices, commodities and more?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can get this indicator completely FREE by upgrading your MetaTrader 5 trading platform provided by Admiral Markets UK Ltd to the exclusive Admiral Markets Supreme Edition!</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-se"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/MT5_SE_dark-2.png" alt="Download MetaTrader 5 Supreme Edition " /></a></p>
<p><b><em>INFORMATION ABOUT ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</em></b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The given data provides additional information regarding all analysis, estimates, prognosis, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other similar assessments or information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the website of Admiral Markets. Before making any investment decisions please pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">1.This is a marketing communication. The content is published for informative purposes only and is in no way to be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and that it is not subject to any prohibition on dealing ahead of the dissemination of investment research.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">2.Any investment decision is made by each client alone whereas Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) shall not be responsible for any loss or damage arising from any such decision, whether or not based on the content.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">3.With view to protecting the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">4.The Analysis is prepared by an independent analyst Jitan Solanki, Freelance Contributor (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimations.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">5.Whilst every reasonable effort is taken to ensure that all sources of the content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, precise and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of any information contained within the Analysis.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">6.Any kind of past or modelled performance of financial instruments indicated within the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee or implication by Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may both increase and decrease and the preservation of the asset value is not guaranteed.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7.Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may result in losses or profit. Before you start trading, please ensure that you fully understand the</span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com.au/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> risks involved</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 23:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/5fe080a524aa21608548517.jpeg" length="204020" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/weekly-market-outlook-21-dec</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/weekly-market-outlook-21-dec</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Weekly Market Outlook: Vaccine approval, Brexit negotiations and more</title>
                <dc:creator>Jeremy Miller</dc:creator>
                <description>The Pfizer Covid vaccine, Brexit negotiations and the Federal Reserve meeting are in the spotlight leading up to the holidays</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p>
	<a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/weekly-outlook-pfizer-brexit"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Weekly_Market_Outlook_vaccine_brexit_fed.jpg" alt="Weekly Market Outlook: Vaccine approval, Brexit negotiations and more" rel="" style=""></a>
</p><p>
	Three decisive news items are expected to direct the course of the market throughout this week, as we head towards the Christmas holidays:
</p><ul>
	<li>The FDA's approval to start the vaccination process in the US after the Pfizer vaccine was approved</li>
	<li>The continuation of post-Brexit trade negotiations between the UK and the European Union</li>
	<li>The meeting of the Federal Reserve </li>
</ul><h2>The Vaccination Process Commences in the US</h2><p>
	Following the FDA's approval of the Pfizer vaccine on Sunday, the United States has followed in the footsteps of the UK and other countries in taking a major step forward in the ongoing fight against the coronavirus pandemic.
</p><p>
	Few countries have been ravaged by the pandemic to the extent of the US, which last week set a record of 234,000 new recorded infections in 24 hours, surpassing a total of 16 million total recorded cases and 302,762 deaths since the pandemic began.
</p><p>
	The vaccination rollout has been approved in principle as an emergency measure for people over 16 years of age with a total of 2.9 million doses ready for distribution.
</p><h2>Brexit Trade Negotiations to Continue</h2><p>
	Last week was a critical week for trade negotiations between the EU and the UK. Sunday had been agreed by both sides as a deadline for reaching an agreement between London and Brussels.
</p><p>
	But once again, as Europe waited in anticipation of a decisive announcement, an extension to the negotiations was announced in an attempt to reach an agreement. Boris Johnson and Ursula Von der Leyen agreed to the extension by telephone on Sunday afternoon, proving, if it was not already clear, that both parties view an agreement as vital, despite their respective positions seeming far apart from an outside perspective.
</p><p>
	Ever since the UK's referendum on membership of the EU in June 2016, the story of Brexit seems to be one which is never ending and less than one month now remains until the transitional period between the two parties comes to an end.
</p><p>
	Last week saw important steps taken, after the British Prime Minister announced the withdrawal of certain controversial clauses within the Internal Market Act, which were in direct contravention of the withdrawal agreement reached last January with the EU regarding the Irish border.
</p><p>
	This new extension will give some breathing space to the financial markets which were rife with uncertainty last week. However, until an agreement is reached, this uncertainty will continue to grow as the chances of a no deal Brexit seem to grow by the day. Countries such as France, Belgium, the Netherlands and Denmark have made it clear that they would prefer no agreement rather than Europe granting too many concessions to the UK.
</p><h2>The Spotlight Shifts to the Federal Reserve</h2><p>
	Last week the President of the European Central Bank, Christine Lagarde, took another step in her plan of doing "whatever it takes" by breathing fresh life into her monetary stimulus program. It is now the turn of the US Federal Reserve to take the reins and assess the possibility of introducing new measures with regards to monetary policy.
</p><p>
	The latest employment data and the situation regarding the pandemic are not at all promising, as the Non-Farm Payroll data from November showed a weakening in the labour market, where unemployment continues to grow.
</p><p>
	It will be important to see what decisions are made, as the $908 billion stimulus package designed to combat the effects of the pandemic remains stalled in negotiations.
</p><p>
	As well as these three key points above, attention must be paid to other events in the economic calendar.
</p><p>
	<em><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Admiral_Markets_Forex_Economic_Calendar-1.png" alt="Admiral Markets Forex Economic Calendar" rel="" style=""></em>
</p><p>
	<em>Source: Admiral Markets Forex Economic Calendar</em>
</p><h2>The Market Situation</h2><p>
	Last week the major global indices closed with slight weekly declines. The DAX30 and the <a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading/contract-specifications/instrument/_sp500_" target="_blank">SP500</a> dropped back to their first support level at their 18 session average.
</p><p>
	It is important to look at the behaviour of both indices and see if they are able to bounce off this level and look for support to take a new upward momentum.
</p><p>
	The loss of these levels could deepen the reversals after the November and early December rises that led to overbought levels in the Stochastic Indicator, so this distribution process could be positive. These reversals could be interpreted as possible entry points for a possible Christmas rally, provided they do not lose their main support levels (moving average of 200 sessions in red). Although for this to happen, the <a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading/contract-specifications/instrument/_dax30_" target="_blank">DAX30</a> will need to break out of its current green resistance level.
</p><p>
	<em><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/DAX30_Daily_Chart.png" alt="DAX30 Daily Chart" rel="" style=""></em>
</p><p>
	<em>Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5 - DAX30 Daily Chart. Date Range: September 9, 2019, to December 11, 2020. Date Captured: December 11, 2020. Past performance is not necessarily an indication of future performance.</em>
</p><p>
	<em><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/SP500_Daily_Chart-1.png" alt="SP500 Daily Chart" rel="" style=""></em>
</p><p>
	<em>Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5 - SP500 Daily Chart. Date Range: September 9, 2019, to December 14, 2020. Date Captured: December 14, 2020. Past performance is not necessarily an indication of future performance.</em>
</p><p>
	On the other hand, the upward trajectory of oil prices following the announcement of successful vaccinations continues to reach levels not seen for the past 8 months. This momentum has been reinforced following OPEC's agreement to increase production by 500,000 barrels per day from January, as opposed to the initially planned 2 million.
</p><p>
	Technically speaking, last week prices closed at $49.89 after rising by 1.92%, continuing November's trends where the price rose over 25%, finally surpassing the high zone of the strong side channel and its average of 200 sessions.
</p><p>
	During the early hours of Monday, <a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading/contract-specifications/instrument/brent" target="_blank">Brent</a> is rising around 1%, thus surpassing the $50 level. It is important to see if it will be able to sustain this break over time and seek new highs. Should it fall back below its previous resistance level (green), the oil could re-enter the laterality whose main support would be the blue band.
</p><p>
	<em><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Brent_Daily_Chart-2.png" rel="" alt="Brent Daily Chart" style=""></em>
</p><p>
	<em>Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5 - Brent Daily Chart. Date Range: September 9, 2019, to December 14, 2020. Date Captured: December 14, 2020. Past performance is not necessarily an indication of future performance.</em>
</p><p>
	In 2015, the value of Brent fell by 35.12%, in 2016, it increased by 45.22%, in 2017, it increased by 18.66%, in 2018, it fell by 21.36% and in 2019, it increased by 25.20%. In five years, therefore, it had risen by 14.38%.
</p><p>
	<br>
</p><h2>Discover Trading with MetaTrader 5</h2><p>
	Admiral Markets offers traders the number 1 multi-asset trading platform in the world completely free! MetaTrader 5 enables traders access to superior charting capabilities, free real-time market data &amp; analysis, the best trading widgets available, and much more! Click the banner below to start your free download:
</p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-5"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/MT5_CTA-15.png" alt="Trade With MetaTrader 5" rel="" style=""><p><br></p></a><p><em><strong data-redactor-tag="strong">INFORMATION ABOUT ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</strong></em></p><p><em>The given data provides additional information regarding all analysis, estimates, prognosis, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other similar assessments or information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the website of Admiral Markets. Before making any investment decisions please pay close attention to the following:</em></p><p><em>1.This is a marketing communication. The content is published for informative purposes only and is in no way to be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and that it is not subject to any prohibition on dealing ahead of the dissemination of investment research.</em></p><p><em>2.Any investment decision is made by each client alone whereas Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) shall not be responsible for any loss or damage arising from any such decision, whether or not based on the content.</em></p><p><em>3.With a view to protecting the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</em></p><p><em>4.The Analysis is prepared by an independent analyst Roberto Rojas, Freelance Contributor (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimations.</em></p><p><em>5.Whilst every reasonable effort is taken to ensure that all sources of the content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, precise and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of any information contained within the Analysis.</em></p><p><em>6.Any kind of past or modelled performance of financial instruments indicated within the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee or implication by Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may both increase and decrease and the preservation of the asset value is not guaranteed.</em></p><p><em>7.Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may result in losses or profit. Before you start trading, please ensure that you fully understand the </em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/risk-disclosure" target="_blank"><em>risks involved</em></a><em>.</em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 01:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/5fd75d0d66d611607949581.jpeg" length="149400" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/weekly-outlook-pfizer-brexit</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/vn/analytics/fundamental-analysis/weekly-outlook-pfizer-brexit</guid>
            </item>
            </channel>
</rss>
