<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>Technical Analysis</title>
        <description>Charts may show the trend, but analysis of indicators and patterns by experts forecast them. See what the statistics say.</description>
        <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis?regulator=cysec</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 11:38:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
                    <item>
                <title>Will gold’s double bottom trigger a 15% rally higher?</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>Gold has formed a double bottom at key technical support levels. Can it start a 15% rally higher?</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-gold-20-jan?regulator=cysec"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_87457911511611140908150.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gold prices enjoyed an impressive +40% rally higher during the coronavirus pandemic before falling for the last few months of 2020. After a push higher in late December, buyers could still not break the 1,950.00 level sending gold prices crashing lower to 1,819.00.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, at this level, the price of gold has put in a double bottom pattern which is seen as a bullish technical sign. On 11 January and 18 January, the price of gold tried to break through the 1,819.00 price level but failed to close below it.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_46999253821611140975203.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5 Web, Gold, Daily - Data range: from May 27, 2020, to Jan 20, 2021, performed on Jan 20, 2021, at 7:30 am GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last five-year performance: 2020 =&nbsp; +25.13%, 2019 = +18.30%, 2018 = -1.60%, 2017 = +13.17%, 2016 = +8.55%, 2015 = -10.30%.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This could be a sign that sellers are now struggling to push the market lower, allowing the opportunity for buyers to step in.&nbsp;</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A close above the recent swing high at 1,864.00 would be a sign buyers are willing to take control of the market where initial targets would be previous horizontal resistance at around the 1,950.00 level.&nbsp;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A close below the double bottom pattern at around 1,803.00 would invalidate the bullish scenario and may encourage sellers to push the market lower, with traders targeting the next swing low at around the 1,764.00 price level.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Much of the flows may depend on the direction of the US dollar. The greenback has been one of the weakest currencies in recent months but has started to stage a potential reversal. If US dollar bulls take control of the US dollar it could spell trouble for gold. However, with new Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen and her new policies, some analysts are forecasting more downside for the US dollar which could help lift gold prices.&nbsp;</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learn more about commodity trading in the &lsquo;</span><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/general-trading/trade-commodities"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to Start Commodity Trading</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rsquo; article.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that you can use the Trading Central Technical Ideas Lookup indicator to find actionable trading ideas on this index and thousands of other instruments across Forex, stocks, indices, commodities and more?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can get this indicator completely FREE by upgrading your MetaTrader 5 trading platform provided by Admiral Markets UK Ltd to the exclusive Admiral Markets Supreme Edition! You&rsquo;ll also receive a whole range of advanced trading tools such as correlation and sentiment indicators!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start your free download by clicking on the banner below:</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-se"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/MT5_SE_dark-2.png" alt="Download MetaTrader 5 Supreme Edition " /></a></p>
<p><b><em>INFORMATION ABOUT ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</em></b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The given data provides additional information regarding all analysis, estimates, prognosis, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other similar assessments or information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the website of Admiral Markets. Before making any investment decisions please pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">1.This is a marketing communication. The content is published for informative purposes only and is in no way to be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and that it is not subject to any prohibition on dealing ahead of the dissemination of investment research.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">2.Any investment decision is made by each client alone whereas Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) shall not be responsible for any loss or damage arising from any such decision, whether or not based on the content.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">3.With view to protecting the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">4.The Analysis is prepared by an independent analyst Jitan Solanki, Freelance Contributor (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimations.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">5.Whilst every reasonable effort is taken to ensure that all sources of the content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, precise and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of any information contained within the Analysis.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">6.Any kind of past or modelled performance of financial instruments indicated within the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee or implication by Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may both increase and decrease and the preservation of the asset value is not guaranteed.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7.Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may result in losses or profit. Before you start trading, please ensure that you fully understand the</span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com.au/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> risks involved</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/60080f98116fa1611141016.jpeg" length="146415" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-gold-20-jan?regulator=cysec</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-gold-20-jan?regulator=cysec</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Carrefour stock falls after the denial of the merger with Couche-Tard</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>Couche-Tard merger offer to Carrefour is withdrawn after the French Government&#039;s refusal of the proposal. Shares in the French chain fall 6%.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/carrefour-stocks-fall?regulator=cysec"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_89327737211610972870257.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Carrefour shares fall by about 6%, and has seen three consecutive days close in the red after the French Government announced its denial of a possible merger with the Canadian group Couche-Tard, which has led the latter to withdraw its interest in negotiating a transaction.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The French supermarket chain closed 13.42% on the Paris Stock Exchange on Wednesday the 13th, after acknowledging preliminary talks with the Canadian company. Thanks to this rise, the value reached its highest highs since July 2019, exceeding 17 euros per share. Now, however, it is once again trading at the threshold of 15 euros. If it continues down, it could fall to the next support, at 14.8 euros per share.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_31183850521610972938657.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5. Carrefour daily chart. Data range: from November 23, 2018 to January 18, 2021. Prepared on January 18, 2021 at 12:30 p.m. Keep in mind that past returns do not guarantee future returns.</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Carrefour has not done well on the stock market in recent years, so last Wednesday's rise sparked optimism among investors. The refusal of the French Government, however, has meant a setback and a wave of liquidation.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Carrefour&rsquo;s performance over the last five years has been: 2020, -6.15%; 2019, 0.27%; 2018, -17.35%; 2017, -21.19%; 2016, -14.11%. So far this month, it has accumulated an increase of 11% at the moment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With an Admiral Markets Trade.MT5 account, you can trade Contracts for Difference (CFDs) on Carrefour and over 3,000 stocks! CFDs allow traders to try to profit from both bull and bear markets, as well as profit from the use of leverage. Click on the following banner to open an account today:</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Live_Account-14.png" alt="Trade Forex &amp; CFDs" /></a></p>
<p><b><em>INFORMATION ON ANALYTICAL MATERIALS</em></b><b>:</b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The data provided provides additional information on all analyzes, estimates, forecasts, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other evaluations or similar information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the Admiral Markets website. Before making any investment decisions, pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<ol>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This is a marketing communication. The content is posted for informational purposes only and should not be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and is not subject to any prohibition on pre-dissemination of investment research.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Each investment decision is made by each client alone, while Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) will not be liable for any loss or damage arising from such a decision, whether based on content or not.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> In order to protect the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for the prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The analysis is prepared by an independent analyst, Carolina Caro, SEO implementer (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimates.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> While all reasonable efforts are made to ensure that all sources of content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, accurate, and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee accuracy. or integrity of any information contained in the Analysis.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Any past performance or modelling of the financial instruments indicated in the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee, or implication of Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may rise and fall, and the preservation of the asset's value is not guaranteed.</span></em></li>
</ol>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7. Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may generate profit or loss. Before you start trading, make sure you fully understand the </span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">risks</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/60057f31397f91610972977.jpeg" length="176251" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/carrefour-stocks-fall?regulator=cysec</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/carrefour-stocks-fall?regulator=cysec</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Will Facebook fall another 10% lower to key support?</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>Discover the most important technical analysis levels to watch in leading tech stocks like Facebook and others for this coming week.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-facebook-15-jan?regulator=cysec"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_16170734011610699842418.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">FAANG stocks have borne the brunt of lofty valuations in the technology sector this week with most of them declining. Interestingly though, there have been flows in other smaller technology companies that investors are now falling in love with.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This rotation of exiting stocks that have reached a peak and reinvesting into cheaper stocks but in the same sector has been the hallmark of this year and could continue for some time. This also means the big heavyweight stocks could continue to suffer.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, Facebook shares have already fallen 10% this year, breaking through key daily and weekly support levels. Traders may now be eyeing the next levels of support on the monthly chart - areas which may also interest long-term buyers.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_7765880021610699933682.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5, #FB, Monthly - Data range: from May 1, 2013, to Jan 14, 2021, performed on Jan 14, 2021, at 8:30 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The monthly chart above shows the weakness that is currently affecting Facebook&rsquo;s share price. However, there is a significant zonal area of support between 225.00 and 201.00. This support zone is comprised of historical horizontal support shown by the black dotted lines, as well as the 50% - 61.8% Fibonacci retracement levels from the swing low from March 2020 to the swing high from September 2020.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A fall to these levels would result in another 10% fall in the stock price. The move lower may be quite choppy, however, as the markets expect an announcement of a significant stimulus package from incoming US president Joe Biden. These could also be interesting for longer-term investors.&nbsp;</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learn more about the 11 sectors of the stock market that every investor needs to know about and how to trade them in the &lsquo;</span><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/shares/stock-sectors"><span style="font-weight: 400;">11 Sectors of the Stock Market You Need to Know!</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rsquo; article.&nbsp;</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to BarChart, analysts still remain long-term bullish on Facebook&rsquo;s share price, as shown below:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_55384047331610699944916.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: </span></em><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.barchart.com/stocks/quotes/GOOG/analyst-ratings"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">BarChart</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">, January 14, 2021</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that you can use the Trading Central Technical Ideas Lookup indicator to find actionable trading ideas on this index and thousands of other instruments across Forex, stocks, indices, commodities and more?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can get this indicator completely FREE by upgrading your MetaTrader 5 trading platform provided by Admiral Markets UK Ltd to the exclusive Admiral Markets Supreme Edition! You&rsquo;ll also receive a whole range of advanced trading tools such as correlation and sentiment indicators!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start your free download by clicking on the banner below:</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-se"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/MT5_SE_dark-2.png" alt="Download MetaTrader 5 Supreme Edition " /></a></p>
<p><b><em>INFORMATION ABOUT ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</em></b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The given data provides additional information regarding all analysis, estimates, prognosis, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other similar assessments or information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the website of Admiral Markets. Before making any investment decisions please pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">1.This is a marketing communication. The content is published for informative purposes only and is in no way to be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and that it is not subject to any prohibition on dealing ahead of the dissemination of investment research.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">2.Any investment decision is made by each client alone whereas Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) shall not be responsible for any loss or damage arising from any such decision, whether or not based on the content.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">3.With view to protecting the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">4.The Analysis is prepared by an independent analyst Jitan Solanki, Freelance Contributor (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimations.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">5.Whilst every reasonable effort is taken to ensure that all sources of the content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, precise and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of any information contained within the Analysis.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">6.Any kind of past or modelled performance of financial instruments indicated within the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee or implication by Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may both increase and decrease and the preservation of the asset value is not guaranteed.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7.Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may result in losses or profit. Before you start trading, please ensure that you fully understand the</span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com.au/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> risks involved</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/600154cd826251610699981.jpeg" length="188376" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-facebook-15-jan?regulator=cysec</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-facebook-15-jan?regulator=cysec</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Will gold complete its near 10% drop this month?</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>Gold has experienced some big moves to the upside and downside in recent months. What’s next for the yellow metal with a rising stock market and US dollar?</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-gold-13-jan?regulator=cysec"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_6271674011610525677468.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since gold&rsquo;s impressive +40% rally from the March lows after the coronavirus pandemic, it peaked in August last year before falling 15% for the rest of the year, as the weekly chart shows below. Since December, gold bulls tried to push the price of the yellow gold higher in anticipation of the typical seasonal rally in January.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_76842161921610525393164.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets </span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-5"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">MetaTrader 5,</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Gold, Weekly - Data range: from Jul 16, 2021, to Jan 12, 2021, performed on Jan 12, 2021, at 7:30 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last five-year performance: 2020 =&nbsp; +25.13%, 2019 = +18.30%, 2018 = -1.60%, 2017 = +13.17%, 2016 = +8.55%, 2015 = -10.30%.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, after a push higher for the first few days of the year gold found technical resistance at the 1,950.00 price level which was around the high of November 2020. In the daily chart below, the horizontal resistance line caused buyers to exit and sellers to step in, as shown by the bearish engulfing candle in the yellow box.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_34349613931610525403345.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5, Gold, Daily - Data range: from Apr 29, 2021, to Jan 12, 2021, performed on Jan 12, 2021, at 7:30 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the market is currently experiencing high levels of volatility, it seems as though sellers are in control for now. Taking a bigger picture perspective from the weekly chart there is potential for gold to fall back down to key support around the 1,765 price level.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This horizontal support line, shown by the dotted line in the weekly chart below, also corresponds closely to the ascending trend line support shown by the thick black line below.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_87836067241610525426472.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets </span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-5"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">MetaTrader 5,</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Gold, Weekly - Data range: from Jul 16, 2021, to Jan 12, 2021, performed on Jan 12, 2021, at 7:30 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A fall back to these support levels would represent a near 10% drop since the rejection of November 2020&rsquo;s high earlier this year. While January tends to be a seasonally bullish period for gold and other metals, investors are currently favouring stock market returns with US indices and the DAX 30 trading at record highs.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The US dollar has also started a potential short-covering rally higher after months of declines. That could also pressure gold towards the downside as traders favour the US dollar once more. However, the levels are clear on where to operate from with patience and discipline required to navigate such volatility.&nbsp;</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learn more about commodity trading in the &lsquo;</span><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/general-trading/trade-commodities"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to Start Commodity Trading</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rsquo; article.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that you can use the Trading Central Technical Ideas Lookup indicator to find actionable trading ideas on this index and thousands of other instruments across Forex, stocks, indices, commodities and more?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can get this indicator completely FREE by upgrading your MetaTrader 5 trading platform provided by Admiral Markets UK Ltd to the exclusive Admiral Markets Supreme Edition! You&rsquo;ll also receive a whole range of advanced trading tools such as correlation and sentiment indicators!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start your free download by clicking on the banner below:</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-se"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/MT5_SE_dark-2.png" alt="Download MetaTrader 5 Supreme Edition " /></a></p>
<p><b><em>INFORMATION ABOUT ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</em></b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The given data provides additional information regarding all analysis, estimates, prognosis, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other similar assessments or information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the website of Admiral Markets. Before making any investment decisions please pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">1.This is a marketing communication. The content is published for informative purposes only and is in no way to be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and that it is not subject to any prohibition on dealing ahead of the dissemination of investment research.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">2.Any investment decision is made by each client alone whereas Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) shall not be responsible for any loss or damage arising from any such decision, whether or not based on the content.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">3.With view to protecting the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">4.The Analysis is prepared by an independent analyst Jitan Solanki, Freelance Contributor (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimations.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">5.Whilst every reasonable effort is taken to ensure that all sources of the content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, precise and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of any information contained within the Analysis.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">6.Any kind of past or modelled performance of financial instruments indicated within the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee or implication by Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may both increase and decrease and the preservation of the asset value is not guaranteed.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7.Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may result in losses or profit. Before you start trading, please ensure that you fully understand the</span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com.au/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> risks involved</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/5ffeac0060a161610525696.jpeg" length="149153" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-gold-13-jan?regulator=cysec</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-gold-13-jan?regulator=cysec</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>The dollar index is trading close to critical support</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>The Forex market begins 2021 with a very similar situation to last year, find out what we can expect for the future in the short term.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/forex-market-begins-2021?regulator=cysec"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_61025259411610365536267.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As highlighted in our weekly report, last year, the US dollar displayed weakness against the other major currencies and, so far this year, this trend has continued. The dollar index is in a zone close to the critical support level of 90.00, so a confirmation of a downward break could prolong this weakness.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The US dollar&rsquo;s weakness can be explained for several reasons:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The coronavirus pandemic. This global crisis has caused the Fed to strengthen monetary stimulus policies, liquidity injections and low interest rate policy.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Weakness in the labour market. The NFP released in December and the one released last week have both been far worse than anticipated.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Political and social instability within the US.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dollar weakness may also be part of a strategy to make US companies more attractive and competitive in the export market, thereby boosting the main stock market indices. These, after sharp falls at the beginning of the pandemic, ended 2020 at historically high levels, particularly the Nasdaq which saw large rises.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">EURUSD Analysis</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Technically speaking, and despite last Friday&rsquo;s poor employment data, last week the EURUSD went through a week of consolidation, dropping from its highs to the 23.6% Fibonacci retracement level of its last bullish momentum. However, the uptrend remains strong after finally breaking out of the side channel. It is not out of the question that the EURUSD could make a correction in the coming days, but provided it does not break below its previous resistance level (green), sentiment will remain bullish and could reach levels close to 1.25.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_32940580341610365677443.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Depicted: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5 - EURUSD Daily Chart. Date Range: 8 October 2019 - 11 January 2021. Date Captured: 11 January 2021. Past performance is not necessarily an indication of future performance.</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Evolution of the last five years:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2020 = +8.93%</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2019 = -2.21%</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2018 = -4.47%</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2017 = +14.09%</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2016 = -3.21%</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">GBPUSD Analysis</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the case of the GBPUSD, we can observe that this pair has been following a very clear uptrend ever since it hit a low of around 1.14100 on 20 March 2020 and has since risen above the 1.37 level.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Currently, as with the EURUSD, the pair is correcting itself from the highs of last week by testing the December 2019 high again. It is important to see if the GBPUSD is able to maintain this support level, in line with its 18-session black average, or whether it will increase this correction to its trend line to seek new momentum, as in previous cases.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the event of breaking the trend line downwards, the price could look for its 200-session average in red, which is close to the 1.30 level. The last support level would be the red line.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_60640115931610365669917.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Depicted: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5 - GBPUSD Daily Chart. Date Range: 11 September 2019 - 11 January 2021. Date Captured: 11 January 2021. Past performance is not necessarily an indication of future performance.</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Evolution of the last five years:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2020 = +3.10%</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2019 = +3.95%</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2018 = -5.54%</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2017 = +9.43%</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2016 = -16.26%</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">USDJPY Analysis</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finally, in the USDJPY, we can see how the Japanese Yen has once again behaved as a major asset since the beginning of the crisis. This is underpinned by the fact that, in times of crises, Japanese investors tend to unwind their overseas positions and seek refuge in their own currency.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This behaviour has led to the price breaching its support level of 104.00 yen per dollar. It will be important to see if it is able to regain this support level or if it continues to fall. The&nbsp; loss of the lower band of the wide channel could lead the USDJPY to look for levels close to or below 100 yen per dollar.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_8766019021610365662895.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Depicted: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5 - USDJPY Weekly Chart. Date Range: 31 August 2014 - 11 January 2021. Date Captured: 11 January 2021. Past performance is not necessarily an indication of future performance.</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Evolution of the last five years:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2020 = -4.95%</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2019 = -0.88%</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2018 = -2.76%</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2017 = -3.59%</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2016 = -2.85%</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Live_Account-14.png" alt="Trade Forex &amp; CFDs" /></a></p>
<p><b><em>INFORMATION ON ANALYTICAL MATERIALS</em></b><b>:</b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The data provided provides additional information on all analyzes, estimates, forecasts, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other evaluations or similar information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the Admiral Markets website. Before making any investment decisions, pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<ol>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This is a marketing communication. The content is posted for informational purposes only and should not be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and is not subject to any prohibition on pre-dissemination of investment research.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Each investment decision is made by each client alone, while Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) will not be liable for any loss or damage arising from such a decision, whether based on content or not.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> In order to protect the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for the prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The analysis is prepared by an independent analyst, Roberto Rojas, SEO implementer (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimates.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> While all reasonable efforts are made to ensure that all sources of content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, accurate, and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee accuracy. or integrity of any information contained in the Analysis.</span></em></li>
<li><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Any past performance or modelling of the financial instruments indicated in the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee, or implication of Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may rise and fall, and the preservation of the asset's value is not guaranteed.</span></em></li>
</ol>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7. Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may generate profit or loss. Before you start trading, make sure you fully understand the </span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">risks</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/5ffc3b18313a51610365720.jpeg" length="187542" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/forex-market-begins-2021?regulator=cysec</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/forex-market-begins-2021?regulator=cysec</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Could Alphabet Inc surge 11% higher from key support?</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>Discover the most important technical analysis levels to watch in the week ahead.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-alphabet-8-jan?regulator=cysec"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_51448514311610101221116.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Technology stocks have taken a beating in recent weeks as investors favoured value stocks instead of growth stocks. However, the sector rotation that has taken place is now seeing signs of a turn with new lockdown restrictions and vaccine rollout concerns forcing investors to move back into tech.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alphabet Inc, the owner of Google, is showing some interesting technical levels on its share price. Over the past few weeks, the company&rsquo;s stock price has struggled to break through two key levels of support, shown on the daily chart below:&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_3765722021610101061042.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5, #GOOG, Daily - Data range: from Apr 9, 2020, to Jan 8, 2021, performed on Jan 8, 2021, at 8:30 am GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results. Last five-year performance: 2020 = +7.89%, 2019 = -5.27%, 2018 = -2.11%, 2017 = +1.48%, 2016 = -3.97%, 2015 = +6.28%.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first support level is shown by the black horizontal line. This was created by the swing high at 1,717.99 during August 2020 which caused a temporary sell-off. When the price came back up and broke through it, the price level became a support level with more than four bounces to the upside since.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second support level is the 50-period exponential moving average (red line). Moving averages are widely used in trending markets and currently confirm the trend is up with the 50-period, 100-period (green line) and 200-period (blue line) all pushing higher.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This week price bounced off both of these support levels for a potential move upwards. Traders will now be looking for additional signs of whether the market will continue its push higher, such as drilling to lower timeframes and viewing cycle formations.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If price can continue, traders may look to the 1,1888.00 price level, which is the 1.272 Fibonacci Extension from the 3 December 2020 swing high to the 21 December swing low, representing a near 11% push higher from December lows.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learn more about chart patterns and price action strategies in the &lsquo;</span><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/forex-strategy/forex-price-action-trading-strategy"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Price Action Trading Strategies</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rsquo; article.&nbsp;</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to BarChart, there has been a huge shift in bullish analyst ratings for Alphabet stock, as shown below:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_56453331831610101070722.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: </span></em><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.barchart.com/stocks/quotes/GOOG/analyst-ratings"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">BarChart</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">, January 8, 2021</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that you can use the Trading Central Technical Ideas Lookup indicator to find actionable trading ideas on this index and thousands of other instruments across Forex, stocks, indices, commodities and more?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can get this indicator completely FREE by upgrading your MetaTrader 5 trading platform provided by Admiral Markets UK Ltd to the exclusive Admiral Markets Supreme Edition! You&rsquo;ll also receive a whole range of advanced trading tools such as correlation and sentiment indicators!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start your free download by clicking on the banner below:</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-se"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/MT5_SE_dark-2.png" alt="Download MetaTrader 5 Supreme Edition " /></a></p>
<p><b><em>INFORMATION ABOUT ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</em></b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The given data provides additional information regarding all analysis, estimates, prognosis, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other similar assessments or information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the website of Admiral Markets. Before making any investment decisions please pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">1.This is a marketing communication. The content is published for informative purposes only and is in no way to be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and that it is not subject to any prohibition on dealing ahead of the dissemination of investment research.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">2.Any investment decision is made by each client alone whereas Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) shall not be responsible for any loss or damage arising from any such decision, whether or not based on the content.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">3.With view to protecting the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">4.The Analysis is prepared by an independent analyst Jitan Solanki, Freelance Contributor (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimations.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">5.Whilst every reasonable effort is taken to ensure that all sources of the content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, precise and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of any information contained within the Analysis.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">6.Any kind of past or modelled performance of financial instruments indicated within the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee or implication by Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may both increase and decrease and the preservation of the asset value is not guaranteed.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7.Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may result in losses or profit. Before you start trading, please ensure that you fully understand the</span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com.au/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> risks involved</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/5ff831f6495281610101238.jpeg" length="169061" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-alphabet-8-jan?regulator=cysec</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-alphabet-8-jan?regulator=cysec</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Can silver surge another 80% higher?</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>There was a historic rally in Silver last year, seeing gains up to 153%. Are we seeing this kind of rally happening in 2021?</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-silver-5-jan?regulator=cysec"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_18737933111609921032899.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Silver enjoyed an incredible rally in 2020, rallying 153% from its March low to August high. While prices retraced during the August to November period, they have been pushing higher since.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In December, the weekly chart formed a bullish engulfing bar which set up a potential push upwards of nearly 34% back to its previous swing high of 29.93 made in August 2020.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While this target may suit shorter-term traders, longer-term investors may well be focused on the all-time high price level of 49.70 made in April 2011 - marking an 80% rally higher from current levels.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_56346634831609921078876.png" /></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets </span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-5"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">MetaTrader 5,</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading/contract-specifications/instrument/silver"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Silver</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Monthly - Data range: from Dec 1, 2005, to Jan 5, 2021, performed on Jan 5, 2021, at 7:30 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The above long-term monthly chart shows a clear break from the lower horizontal line at 21.13. Now that price has strongly broken above this price level, it opens up the doorway for further upside. The all-time high is quite far off and is most likely suited for longer-term investors.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, shorter-term traders could also capitalise on these flows by drilling down the lower timeframes. For example, the daily chart shows a clear uptrend forming with higher high and higher low cycles, as well as bullish moving average alignment with the 50-period (red), 100-period (green) and 200-period (black) exponential moving averages all pointing upwards, as shown below:</span></p>
<p><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_65529799721609921067515.png" /></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets </span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-5"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">MetaTrader 5,</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Silver, Daily - Data range: from Apr 14, 2020, to Jan 5, 2021, performed on Jan 5, 2021, at 8:30 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the above daily chart shows a downwards trend from August to November 2020, the price made a double bottom price pattern at the 21.89 level which is in-between the 100-period and 200-period exponential moving averages.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Traders may look for pullbacks to the ascending trend line support shown via the black line on the chart or any of the moving averages. However, as silver is a key component in electric vehicles demand may ramp up making the trend even more aggressive, causing traders to further drill down to lower timeframes such as the four-hour chart to find potential opportunities.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learn more about commodity trading in the &lsquo;</span><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/general-trading/trade-commodities"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to Start Commodity Trading</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rsquo; article.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that you can use the Trading Central Technical Ideas Lookup indicator to find actionable trading ideas on this index and thousands of other instruments across Forex, stocks, indices, commodities and more?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can get this indicator completely FREE by upgrading your MetaTrader 5 trading platform provided by Admiral Markets UK Ltd to the exclusive Admiral Markets Supreme Edition! You&rsquo;ll also receive a whole range of advanced trading tools such as correlation and sentiment indicators!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start your free download by clicking on the banner below:</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-se"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/MT5_SE_dark-2.png" alt="Download MetaTrader 5 Supreme Edition " /></a></p>
<p><b><em>INFORMATION ABOUT ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</em></b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The given data provides additional information regarding all analysis, estimates, prognosis, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other similar assessments or information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the website of Admiral Markets. Before making any investment decisions please pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">1.This is a marketing communication. The content is published for informative purposes only and is in no way to be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and that it is not subject to any prohibition on dealing ahead of the dissemination of investment research.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">2.Any investment decision is made by each client alone whereas Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) shall not be responsible for any loss or damage arising from any such decision, whether or not based on the content.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">3.With view to protecting the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">4.The Analysis is prepared by an independent analyst Jitan Solanki, Freelance Contributor (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimations.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">5.Whilst every reasonable effort is taken to ensure that all sources of the content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, precise and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of any information contained within the Analysis.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">6.Any kind of past or modelled performance of financial instruments indicated within the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee or implication by Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may both increase and decrease and the preservation of the asset value is not guaranteed.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7.Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may result in losses or profit. Before you start trading, please ensure that you fully understand the</span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com.au/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> risks involved</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/5ff57294f33951609921172.jpeg" length="294446" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-silver-5-jan?regulator=cysec</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-silver-5-jan?regulator=cysec</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>The year 2020 ended with Wall Street at all-time highs.</title>
                <dc:creator>Kyle Martin</dc:creator>
                <description>After the strong falls suffered at the beginning of the pandemic, the second half of 2020 saw a strong recovery in the main stock exchanges.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/stock-highs-2021?regulator=cysec"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_15997626811609759054809.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2020 will be remembered as the year of lockdowns and uncertainty due to the global crisis caused by the Coronavirus pandemic that began in February.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fear and uncertainty of this situation caused sharp falls in the stock markets and in oil due to the closures that occurred in practically all the countries of the world, generating strong declines in GDP along with a strong destruction of jobs worldwide, although the situation was improving thanks to the different stimulus programs carried out by different countries and international organizations to try to alleviate this crisis.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hope came during November, after positive results of the vaccines in development were made public, along with the start of the vaccination process during December with approval from the FDA, the European Union, and the United Kingdom.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite this, the positive performance of the major stock market indices in 2020, some reaching historic highs, is another indication of the decoupling between the real economy and the financial markets. If we analyse the situation in depth, we can see that economies have been heavily influenced by government aid, low interest rates and liquidity injection policies through debt purchases by central banks. We can, therefore, observe a dramatic increase in the level of national debt in various countries, making debt levels look very challenging.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the other hand, 2020 has also left us with an agreement between the EU and the UK regarding future trade, meaning we can finally put an end to this issue which has seemed like a never-ending story since the UK&rsquo;s referendum in 2016.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If we focus on the US indices, we can see that last year, the SP500, NQ100 and DJI30 ended the year with record highs, with annual increases of 15.5%, 43.4% and 6.6% respectively.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Without doubt, the great protagonist was the NASDAQ, thanks to the strong performance of technology stocks, such as Apple, Amazon and Tesla. At the end of March, after the sharp falls at the beginning of the pandemic,&nbsp; it had reached annual lows of around 6,640 points. From this low, there was an incredible bullish rally that led, not only to it recording a historic high, but also coming close to reaching 13,000 points.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite the overbought levels that we can see in the stochastic indicator, the upward trend seems intact, with its 3 moving averages up and the price repeatedly supported by its 18-session average in black. As long as the price does not lose its previous resistance level, which now acts as its main support level (red line below), we do not expect a further correction.</span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_45360059721609759108831.png" /></span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5 Supreme Edition platform NQ100 daily chart (from October 4, 2019 to January 4, 2021). Taken on January 4, 2021. Note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results or future performance.</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2016, the NQ100 rose by 5.89%, in 2017 by 31.52%, in 2018 by 1.04%, in 2019 by 37.96% and in 2020 by 43.4%.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If we shift focus to Europe, we can see how the DAX30 rose by around 3.6% last year, leading the German index to record highs. Other indices, such as the Euro Stoxx, CAC40, IBEX35 and the FTSE100, lost around 5.1%, 7.1%, 15.5% and 14.3% respectively, despite also experiencing strong rises following losses at the beginning of the pandemic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If we look at the daily chart below, we can see that the upward trend has taken on a new impulse after the definitive break of its previous resistance level (green) from the strong lateral movement that it took during the second half of the year. The break of this resistance led to it overcoming its previous historical high.</span></p>
<p><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/mceu_70427588631609759115065.png" /></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: DAX30 daily chart from Admiral Markets MetaTrader 5 Supreme Edition platform (from August 22, 2019 to January 4, 2021). Taken on January 4, 2021. Note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results or future performance.</span></em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2016 it rose by 6.87%, in 2017 by 12.51%, in 2018 it lost 18.26% in 2019 it rose by 25.48% and in 2020 it rose by 3, 6%</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Discover the world&rsquo;s #1 multi-asset platform</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Admiral Markets offers professional traders the ability to trade with MetaTrader 5, allowing you to experience trading at a significantly higher, more rewarding level than with MetaTrader 4. Experience benefits such as the addition of the Market Heat Map, so you can compare various currency pairs to see which ones might be lucrative investments, access real-time trading data, and so much more. Click the banner below to start your FREE download of MT5!</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-5"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/MT5_CTA-15.png" alt="Trade With MetaTrader 5" /></a></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Disclaimer: The given data provides additional information regarding all analysis, estimates, prognosis, forecasts or other similar assessments or information (hereinafter &ldquo;Analysis&rdquo;) published on the website of Admiral Markets. Before making any investment decisions please pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is a marketing communication.&nbsp;The analysis is published for informative purposes only and is in no way to be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and that it is not subject to any prohibition on dealing ahead of the dissemination of investment research.</span></em></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Any investment decision is made by each client alone whereas Admiral Markets shall not be responsible for any loss or damage arising from any such decision, whether or not based on the Analysis.</span></em></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Each of the Analysis is prepared by an independent analyst (Roberto Rojas</span></em><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp;hereinafter &ldquo;Author&rdquo;) based on the Author&rsquo;s personal estimations.&nbsp;</span></em></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">To ensure that the interests of the clients would be protected and objectivity of the Analysis would not be damaged Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whilst every reasonable effort is taken to ensure that all sources of the Analysis are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, precise and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of any information contained within the Analysis. The presented figures that refer to any past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.</span></em></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The contents of the Analysis should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee or implication by Admiral Markets that the client shall profit from the strategies therein or that losses in connection therewith may or shall be limited.</span></em></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Any kind of previous or modelled performance of financial instruments indicated within the Publication should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee or implication by Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may both increase and decrease and the preservation of the asset value is not guaranteed.</span></em></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The projections included in the Analysis may be subject to additional fees, taxes or other charges, depending on the subject of the Publication. The price list applicable to the services provided by Admiral Markets is publicly available from the website of Admiral Markets.</span></em></li>
</ul>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may result in losses or profit. Before you start trading, you should make sure that you understand all the&nbsp;</span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/risk-disclosure"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">risks</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/5ff2f9e88e48e1609759208.jpeg" length="149833" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/stock-highs-2021?regulator=cysec</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/stock-highs-2021?regulator=cysec</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Google hit with third lawsuit! Buy dip at trend line support?</title>
                <dc:creator>Jeremy Miller</dc:creator>
                <description>Discover the most important technical analysis levels to watch in the week ahead.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/alphabet-google-stock-18-december?regulator=cysec"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Google_hit_with_third_lawsuit.jpg" alt="Google hit with third lawsuit! Buy the dip at trend line support?" width="1440" height="810" /></a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shares in Google&rsquo;s parent company Alphabet have been in full focus as they received a third government antitrust lawsuit in less than two months. Thirty eight states in the United States have joined forces to claim Google maintained a monopoly in general search and search advertising illegally through anti-competitive contracts.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The move is likely to influence investors buying when the stock price is at record highs. In fact, the technical chart looks relatively bullish as the price struggles to break through the 1.272 Fibonacci extension level taken from the 2 September swing high to 23 September swing low, as shown below:&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/GOOG_daily_chart_trend_line_support.png" alt="GOOG daily chart trend line support" width="1600" height="767" /></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets <a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MetaTrader 5</a>, #GOOG, Daily - Data range: from Jul 16, 2020, to Dec 17, 2020, performed on Dec 17, 2020, at 9:30 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last five-year performance: 2019 = +28.18%, 2018 = -0.80%, 2017 = +32.93%, 2016 = +1.86%, 2015 = +46.61%.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fibonacci extension levels are used to help identify potential turning points in the market. At the level highlighted above, the price has also failed to make a higher and has formed a double top fake out chart pattern around the 1,810.17 level.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The price may pull back towards the ascending trend line support level as highlighted by the thick blue line, after all, many investors may think twice about buying a company trading at record highs with three antitrust lawsuits to deal with.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the price can pull back towards the trend line support it may be an area investors may consider to turn up once more.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to BarChart, bullish ratings from analysts have peaked:</span></p>
<p><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/bar_chart_bullish_ratings.png" alt="bar chart bullish ratings" width="1032" height="168" /></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: </span></em><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.barchart.com/stocks/quotes/GOOG/analyst-ratings" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">BarChart</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">, December 17, 2020</span></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that you can use the Trading Central Technical Ideas Lookup indicator to find actionable trading ideas on thousands of instruments across Forex, stocks, indices, commodities and more?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can get this indicator completely FREE by upgrading your MetaTrader 5 trading platform provided by Admiral Markets UK Ltd to the exclusive Admiral Markets Supreme Edition! You&rsquo;ll also receive a whole range of advanced trading tools such as correlation and sentiment indicators!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start your free download by clicking on the banner below:</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-se"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/MT5_SE_dark-2.png" alt="Download MetaTrader 5 Supreme Edition " /></a></p>
<p><b><em>INFORMATION ABOUT ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</em></b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The given data provides additional information regarding all analysis, estimates, prognosis, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other similar assessments or information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the website of Admiral Markets. Before making any investment decisions please pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">1.This is a marketing communication. The content is published for informative purposes only and is in no way to be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and that it is not subject to any prohibition on dealing ahead of the dissemination of investment research.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">2.Any investment decision is made by each client alone whereas Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) shall not be responsible for any loss or damage arising from any such decision, whether or not based on the content.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">3.With view to protecting the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">4.The Analysis is prepared by an independent analyst Jitan Solanki, Freelance Contributor (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimations.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">5.Whilst every reasonable effort is taken to ensure that all sources of the content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, precise and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of any information contained within the Analysis.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">6.Any kind of past or modelled performance of financial instruments indicated within the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee or implication by Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may both increase and decrease and the preservation of the asset value is not guaranteed.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7.Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may result in losses or profit. Before you start trading, please ensure that you fully understand the</span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com.au/risk-disclosure" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> risks involved</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://admiralimages.s3.amazonaws.com/logos/AM_placeholder_940x492.png" length="35077" type="image/png"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/alphabet-google-stock-18-december?regulator=cysec</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/alphabet-google-stock-18-december?regulator=cysec</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Will Gold false breakout and surge 15% higher?</title>
                <dc:creator>Jeremy Miller</dc:creator>
                <description>Discover the most important technical analysis levels to watch in the week ahead.</description>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[ <p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-gold-16-dec?regulator=cysec"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto"   style="width:auto;" class="img-responsive" data-src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/Will_Gold_false_breakout_surge.jpg" alt="gold false breakout surge" width="1440" height="810" /></a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After an incredible 40%+ surge in the price of gold during the coronavirus pandemic earlier this year, the yellow metal has fallen roughly 15% in value. However, with the traditional seasonal rally coming up gold could be in hot demand.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Technically, gold formed a descending triangle formation with a series of lower highs from August as shown by the blue line. After several rejections on the way down, price tried to break out in November only to fail and come back inside the triangle pattern.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Interestingly, the price of gold has now broken through the bottom of the triangle pattern as shown by the black horizontal support line at around 1,863. While the price has since rejected the same level to the downside, momentum has been limited, suggesting a false breakout back to the upside could be likely.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/GOLD_Daily.png" alt="gold daily chart" width="1600" height="767" /></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Source: Admiral Markets </span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-5" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">MetaTrader 5,</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> GOLD, Daily - Data range: from Apr 6, 2020, to Dec 11, 2020, performed on Dec 11, 2020, at 7:30 pm GMT. Please note: Past performance is not a reliable indicator of future results.&nbsp;</span></em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last five-year performance: 2019 = +18.31%, 2018 = -1.60%, 2017 = +13.17%, 2016 = +8.55%, 2015 = -10.30%.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the price of </span><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/start-trading/contract-specifications/instrument/gold" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">gold</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> manages to break back above the resistance line of 1,863, it also coincides with a break of the descending resistance line in blue. A significant close above these levels could bring bulls back to the market in line with a possible end of year rally and traditionally bullish start to the year for precious metals.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A move back to gold&rsquo;s all-time high price level of around 2,064 means a break higher could represent a 15% move up from the November lows.&nbsp;</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learn more about commodity trading in the &lsquo;</span><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/education/articles/general-trading/trade-commodities" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to Start Commodity Trading</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&rsquo; article. &nbsp;</span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that you can use the Trading Central Technical Ideas Lookup indicator to find actionable trading ideas on this index and thousands of other instruments across Forex, stocks, indices, commodities and more?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can get this indicator completely FREE by upgrading your MetaTrader 5 trading platform provided by Admiral Markets UK Ltd to the exclusive Admiral Markets Supreme Edition! You&rsquo;ll also receive a whole range of advanced trading tools such as correlation and sentiment indicators!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start your free download by clicking on the banner below:</span></p>
<p><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com/trading-platforms/metatrader-se"><img data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" data-resize="auto" src="https://fxmedia.s3.amazonaws.com/articles/MT5_SE_dark-2.png" alt="Download MetaTrader 5 Supreme Edition " /></a></p>
<p><b><em>INFORMATION ABOUT ANALYTICAL MATERIALS:</em></b></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">The given data provides additional information regarding all analysis, estimates, prognosis, forecasts, market reviews, weekly outlooks or other similar assessments or information (hereinafter "Analysis") published on the website of Admiral Markets. Before making any investment decisions please pay close attention to the following:</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">1.This is a marketing communication. The content is published for informative purposes only and is in no way to be construed as investment advice or recommendation. It has not been prepared in accordance with legal requirements designed to promote the independence of investment research, and that it is not subject to any prohibition on dealing ahead of the dissemination of investment research.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">2.Any investment decision is made by each client alone whereas Admiral Markets UK Ltd (Admiral Markets) shall not be responsible for any loss or damage arising from any such decision, whether or not based on the content.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">3.With view to protecting the interests of our clients and the objectivity of the Analysis, Admiral Markets has established relevant internal procedures for prevention and management of conflicts of interest.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">4.The Analysis is prepared by an independent analyst Jitan Solanki, Freelance Contributor (hereinafter "Author") based on personal estimations.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">5.Whilst every reasonable effort is taken to ensure that all sources of the content are reliable and that all information is presented, as much as possible, in an understandable, timely, precise and complete manner, Admiral Markets does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of any information contained within the Analysis.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">6.Any kind of past or modelled performance of financial instruments indicated within the content should not be construed as an express or implied promise, guarantee or implication by Admiral Markets for any future performance. The value of the financial instrument may both increase and decrease and the preservation of the asset value is not guaranteed.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">7.Leveraged products (including contracts for difference) are speculative in nature and may result in losses or profit. Before you start trading, please ensure that you fully understand the</span></em><a href="https://admiralmarkets.com.au/risk-disclosure" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> risks involved</span></em></a><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></em></p> ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
                                <enclosure url="https://fxmedia.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/featured_images/5fd9bd60685d01608105312.jpeg" length="303626" type="image/jpg"/>
                                <link>https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-gold-16-dec?regulator=cysec</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://admiralmarkets.com/analytics/technical-analysis/technical-analysis-gold-16-dec?regulator=cysec</guid>
            </item>
            </channel>
</rss>
